<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Martínez Falquina, Silvia</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Da Cruz Carvalho, Angelina</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Abstract In her works, Jesmyn Ward usually deals with her African American community so that her readers will be aware of their difficulties. This is seen in her novel Salvage the Bones (2011), which mainly focuses on the black women’s difficulties with the example of a poor black teenage girl called Esch. This essay intends to demonstrate the importance of the concept “intersectional feminism,” theorized by Crenshaw in 1989 and according to which in order to understand the situation of women of colour, it is essential to study all the elements of their identities together. To show this idea, this essay analyses elements of social and gender discrimination simultaneously, focusing on the character of Esch. Since she and her family are poor and black, they are excluded from the American dream and their behaviour is animalized in the struggle to survive Hurricane Katrina. Moreover, Esch lives in a patriarchal system where she has to adopt certain roles: she has to be a mother for her brothers, be responsible for the domestic chores and be a sexual object for men. To aggravate her situation, she has to cope with motherhood, since she is pregnant. However, in spite of all these difficulties, the ending offers some hope for the family. Esch decides to stay strong, thanks mainly to the inspiration of female figures, her brothers and a special friend. In this way, she is a great example of resilience, since she will be able to rebuild her own family.  Resumen En sus obras, Jesmyn Ward generalmente habla de su comunidad afroamericana para que los lectores se den cuenta de las dificultades de la misma. Esto se observa en su novela Salvage the Bones (2011), que se centra principalmente en las dificultades de las mujeres de raza negra con el ejemplo de una adolescente negra y pobre llamada Esch. Este ensayo tiene la intención de demostrar la importancia del concepto “feminismo interseccional,” teorizado por Crenshaw en 1989, y según el cual para entender la situación de las mujeres de color es esencial estudiar todos los elementos que componen sus identidades en conjunto. Para demostrar esta idea, el ensayo analiza elementos de la discriminación social junto a la de género, con un enfoque en el personaje de Esch. Dado que ella y su familia son pobres y de raza negra, están excluidos del sueño americano y tienen que comportarse como animales para sobrevivir al huracán Katrina. Además, Esch vive en un sistema patriarcal donde tiene que adoptar ciertos papeles: tiene que ser una madre para sus hermanos, encargarse de las tareas domésticas y ser un objeto sexual para los hombres. Para empeorar su situación, tiene que lidiar con la maternidad, ya que está embarazada. Sin embargo, a pesar de todas estas dificultades, el final ofrece algo de esperanza para la familia. Esch decide mantenerse fuerte, principalmente gracias a la inspiración en las figuras femeninas, sus hermanos y un amigo especial. De esta forma, ella es un buen ejemplo de resiliencia, ya que será capaz de reconstruir su propia familia.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75200</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75200/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-1478.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Intersectional Identity and Resilience in Jesmyn Ward's Salvage the Bones</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Intersectional Identity and Resilience in Jesmyn Ward's Salvage the Bones</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
