<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Castro Escario, Elisenda</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Tiendas Martín, Andrea</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>After observing and implementing a learning unit during the Master’s degree placement period, there was a clear need that could be addressed and improved significantly by introducing this paper’s topic: co-teaching. There are two main advantages that co-teaching provides: in the first place, better attention to differentiation and, in the second place, more time to develop resources and teaching styles in order to focus on both production skills: speaking and writing. Aiming at the emphasis that the Aragonese curriculum for EFL lays on the communicative purpose of a foreign language, co-teaching will enhance and create more possibilities for the practice of communicative skills. By means of interactive, original and well-grounded activities and tasks, students will feel engaged toward creating a meaningful product, i.e. a digital poster, which will contain several measures to improve the public transport system in the city of Zaragoza. Thus, the proposed learning unit is a combination of four pedagogical approaches: co-teaching, Communicative Language Teaching, Project-Based Language Learning and Task-Based Language Teaching. It is precisely by the ambitious combination of all four methodologies that students will be achieving mastery in the communicative competence as a whole, while they work on a topic that is relevant to their personal lives. Hopefully, co-teaching becomes a reality sooner than later and both parties involved, students and teachers, can start benefitting from all its advantages. All in all, the proposed learning activities within the unit are meant to be lifelong practice of Foreign Languages.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86732</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86732/files/TAZ-TFM-2019-586.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Introducing co-teaching in a PBLL learning unit: “Redesigning public transport in your city”</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Introducing co-teaching in a PBLL learning unit: “Redesigning public transport in your city”</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
