<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Pascual Oliva, Daniel</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Arregui Larrodé, Isabel</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>In an educational field where technological changes are at the forefront, this unit seeks to contribute to develop students’ communicative competence in English and address the gap in the EFL classroom with regards to production skills: speaking and writing. This is done through a learning unit around the topic of travel and tourism which is developed by means of both a Project Based Language Learning (PBL) and a Cooperative Learning (CL) methodology. After identifying the learners’ needs, and considering the theories surrounding PBL and CL, this dissertation aims to improve speaking and writing in English by implementing a series of lessons that ultimately lead to the production of a podcast. Not only does the Podcasting project allow students to improve their written work, they also strengthen their speaking skills in English through controlled production.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77392</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77392/files/TAZ-TFM-2018-535.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Haciendo eco por el mundo: un proyecto para inglés como lengua extranjera en la educación secundaria</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Sending shockwaves from around the world: a project for english as a foreign language in secondary education</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
