<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Martínez Falquina, Silvia</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Cargol Martínez, Alba</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Abstract Female oppression has led to the apparition of several social and intellectual movements that aim towards women’s liberation. Such movements have been traditionally included under the label of feminism. However, throughout the second half of the 20th century, many female groups started to voice out their discontent towards this term. Due to this, in this period many feminist movements which unified different cultural, racial or social female groups emerged. Among them we find the Xicanisma philosophy which represents women from Mexican heritage and which includes a wide literary and intellectual production, one of its main representatives is Ana Castillo. This essay will analyse Castillo’s novel So Far From God (1993) from a Xicanisma point of view. The main purpose will be to analyse the roles of the five female protagonist of the novel and to evidence how they embody the different aspects that conform Xicanisma ideology. Special attention will be paid to the constant connections between the Chicana feminist movement and Mexican mythology. Therefore, this essay will showcase how traditional elements from the Mexican culture, which are negatively and stereotypically associated with women, such as sexuality or spirituality, are subverted and included within the Xicanisma portfolio as key elements towards female liberation. Resumen La opresión femenina ha desembocado en la aparición de varios movimientos sociales e intelectuales enfocados hacia la liberación de las mujeres. Estas ideas han sido tradicionalmente incluidas bajo la etiqueta de feminismo. Sin embargo, a lo largo de la segunda mitad del siglo XX, distintos grupos de mujeres comenzaron a expresar su descontento hacia este término. Por consiguiente, en este periodo surgieron muchos movimientos feministas que unían a mujeres de diferentes grupos culturales, raciales o sociales. Dentro de los mismos, encontramos el movimiento Xicanisma que representa a mujeres de descendencia mexicana y que incluye una amplia producción literaria e intelectual; una de sus principales representantes es Ana Castillo. En este trabajo se analizará la novela So Far From God (1993) de Castillo desde el punto de vista de la teoría Xicanisma. El objetivo principal será analizar los roles de las cinco protagonistas femeninas de la novela y evidenciar cómo encarnan los diferentes aspectos que conforman la ideología del feminismo Chicano. Se prestará especial atención a las constantes conexiones entre esta corriente y la mitología mexicana. Por lo tanto, este ensayo mostrará cómo elementos tradicionales de la cultura mexicana, comúnmente asociados de manera negativa con las mujeres, como la sexualidad o la espiritualidad, son alterados e incluidos dentro del movimiento Xicanisma como factores clave para su liberación.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75217</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75217/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-1416.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Flying Daughters and Xicanisma Mothers: An Analysis of Ana Castillo’s So Far From God</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Flying Daughters and Xicanisma Mothers: An Analysis of Ana Castillo’s So Far From God</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
