<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Orrite Uruñuela, Carlos</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Rodríguez Martínez, Mario Félix</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2016</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Esta tesis propone nuevas metodologías para el aprendizaje de actividades humanas y su clasificación en categorías. Aunque este tema ha sido ampliamente estudiado por la comunidad investigadora en visión por computador, aún encontramos importantes dificultades por resolver. En primer lugar hemos encontrado que la literatura sobre técnicas de visión por computador para el aprendizaje de actividades humanas empleando pocas secuencias de entrenamiento es escasa y además presenta resultados pobres [1] [2]. Sin embargo, este aprendizaje es una herramienta crucial en varios escenarios. Por ejemplo, un sistema de reconocimiento recién desplegado necesita mucho tiempo para adquirir nuevas secuencias de entrenamiento así que el entrenamiento con pocos ejemplos puede acelerar la puesta en funcionamiento.  También la detección de comportamientos anómalos, ejemplos de los cuales son difíciles de obtener, puede beneficiarse de estas técnicas. Existen soluciones mediante técnicas de cruce dominios o empleando características invariantes, sin embargo estas soluciones omiten información del escenario objetivo la cual reduce el ruido en el sistema mejorando los resultados cuando se tiene en cuenta y ejemplos de actividades anómalas siguen siendo difíciles de obtener. Estos sistemas entrenados con poca información se enfrentan a dos problemas principales: por una parte el sistema de entrenamiento puede sufrir de inestabilidades numéricas en la estimación de los parámetros del modelo, por otra, existe una falta de información representativa proveniente de actividades diversas. Nos hemos enfrentado a estos problemas proponiendo novedosos métodos para el aprendizaje de actividades humanas usando tan solo un ejemplo, lo que se denomina one-shot learning. Nuestras propuestas se basan en sistemas generativos, derivadas de los Modelos Ocultos de Markov[3][4], puesto que cada clase de actividad debe ser aprendida con tan solo un ejemplo. Además, hemos ampliado la diversidad de información en los modelos aplicado una transferencia de información desde fuentes externas al escenario[5]. En esta tesis se explican varias propuestas y se muestra como con ellas hemos conseguidos resultados en el estado del arte en tres bases de datos públicas [6][7][8]. La segunda dificultad a la que nos hemos enfrentado es el reconocimiento de actividades sin restricciones en el escenario. En este caso no tiene por qué coincidir el escenario de entrenamiento y el de evaluación por lo que la reducción de ruido anteriormente expuesta no es aplicable. Esto supone que se pueda emplear cualquier ejemplo etiquetado para entrenamiento independientemente del escenario de origen. Esta libertad nos permite extraer vídeos desde cualquier fuente evitando la restricción en el número de ejemplos de entrenamiento. Teniendo suficientes ejemplos de entrenamiento tanto métodos generativos como discriminativos pueden ser empleados. En el momento de realización de esta tesis encontramos que el estado del arte obtiene los mejores resultados empleando métodos discriminativos, sin embargo, la mayoría de propuestas no suelen considerar la información temporal a largo plazo de las actividades[9]. Esta información puede ser crucial para distinguir entre actividades donde el orden de sub-acciones es determinante, y puede ser una ayuda en otras situaciones[10]. Para ello hemos diseñado un sistema que incluye dicha información en una Máquina de Vectores de Soporte. Además, el sistema permite cierta flexibilidad en la alineación de las secuencias a comparar, característica muy útil si la segmentación de las actividades no es perfecta. Utilizando este sistema hemos obtenido resultados en el estado del arte para cuatro bases de datos complejas sin restricciones en los escenarios[11][12][13][14]. Los trabajos realizados en esta tesis han servido para realizar tres artículos en revistas del primer cuartil [15][16][17], dos ya publicados y otro enviado. Además, se han publicado 8 artículos en congresos internacionales y uno nacional [18][19][20][21][22][23][24][25][26]. [1]Seo, H. J. and Milanfar, P. (2011). Action recognition from one example. IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, 33(5):867–882.(2011) [2]Yang, Y., Saleemi, I., and Shah, M. Discovering motion primitives for unsupervised grouping and one-shot learning of human actions, gestures, and expressions. IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, 35(7):1635–1648. (2013) [3]Rabiner, L. R. A tutorial on hidden markov models and selected applications in speech recognition. Proceedings of the IEEE, 77(2):257–286. (1989) [4]Bishop, C. M. Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning (Information Science and Statistics). Springer-Verlag New York, Inc., Secaucus, NJ, USA. (2006) [5]Cook, D., Feuz, K., and Krishnan, N. Transfer learning for activity recognition: a survey. Knowledge and Information Systems, pages 1–20. (2013) [6]Schuldt, C., Laptev, I., and Caputo, B. Recognizing human actions: a local svm approach. In International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR). (2004) [7]Weinland, D., Ronfard, R., and Boyer, E. Free viewpoint action recognition using motion history volumes. Computer Vision and Image Understanding, 104(2-3):249–257. (2006) [8]Gorelick, L., Blank, M., Shechtman, E., Irani, M., and Basri, R. Actions as space-time shapes. IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, 29(12):2247–2253. (2007) [9]Wang, H. and Schmid, C. Action recognition with improved trajectories. In IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV). (2013) [10]Choi, J., Wang, Z., Lee, S.-C., and Jeon, W. J. A spatio-temporal pyramid matching for video retrieval. Computer Vision and Image Understanding, 117(6):660 – 669. (2013) [11]Oh, S., Hoogs, A., Perera, A., Cuntoor, N., Chen, C.-C., Lee, J. T., Mukherjee, S., Aggarwal, J. K., Lee, H., Davis, L., Swears, E., Wang, X., Ji, Q., Reddy, K., Shah, M., Vondrick, C., Pirsiavash, H., Ramanan, D., Yuen, J., Torralba, A., Song, B., Fong, A., Roy-Chowdhury, A., and Desai, M. A large-scale benchmark dataset for event recognition in surveillance video. In IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), pages 3153–3160. (2011) [12] Niebles, J. C., Chen, C.-W., and Fei-Fei, L. Modeling temporal structure of decomposable motion segments for activity classification. In European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), pages 392–405.(2010) [13]Reddy, K. K. and Shah, M. Recognizing 50 human action categories of web videos. Machine Vision and Applications, 24(5):971–981. (2013) [14]Kuehne, H., Jhuang, H., Garrote, E., Poggio, T., and Serre, T. HMDB: a large video database for human motion recognition. In IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV). (2011) [15]Rodriguez, M., Orrite, C., Medrano, C., and Makris, D. One-shot learning of human activity with an map adapted gmm and simplex-hmm. IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics, PP(99):1–12. (2016) [16]Rodriguez, M., Orrite, C., Medrano, C., and Makris, D. A time flexible kernel framework for video-based activity recognition. Image and Vision Computing 48-49:26 – 36. (2016) [17]Rodriguez, M., Orrite, C., Medrano, C., and Makris, D. Extended Study for One-shot Learning of Human Activity by a Simplex-HMM. IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics (Enviado) [18]Orrite, C., Rodriguez, M., Medrano, C. One-shot learning of temporal sequences using a distance dependent Chinese Restaurant Process. In Proceedings of the 23nd International Conference Pattern Recognition ICPR (December 2016) [19]Rodriguez, M., Medrano, C., Herrero, E., and Orrite, C. Spectral Clustering Using Friendship Path Similarity Proceedings of the 7th Iberian Conference, IbPRIA (June 2015) [20]Orrite, C., Soler, J., Rodriguez, M., Herrero, E., and Casas, R. Image-based location recognition and scenario modelling. In Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Computer Vision Theory and Applications, VISAPP (March 2015) [21]Castán, D., Rodríguez, M., Ortega, A., Orrite, C., and Lleida, E. Vivolab and cvlab - mediaeval 2014: Violent scenes detection affect task. In Working Notes Proceedings of the MediaEval (October 2014) [22]Orrite, C., Rodriguez, M., Herrero, E., Rogez, G., and Velastin, S. A. Automatic segmentation and recognition of human actions in monocular sequences In Proceedings of the 22nd International Conference Pattern Recognition ICPR (August 2014) [23]Rodriguez, M., Medrano, C., Herrero, E., and Orrite, C. Transfer learning of human poses for action recognition. In 4th International Workshop of Human Behavior Unterstanding (HBU). (October 2013) [24]Rodriguez, M., Orrite, C., and Medrano, C. Human action recognition with limited labelled data. In Actas del III Workshop de Reconocimiento de Formas y Analisis de Imagenes, WSRFAI. (September 2013) [25]Orrite, C., Monforte, P., Rodriguez, M., and Herrero, E. Human Action Recognition under Partial Occlusions . Proceedings of the 6th Iberian Conference, IbPRIA (June 2013) [26]Orrite, C., Rodriguez, M., and Montañes, M. One sequence learning of human actions. In 2nd International Workshop of Human Behavior Unterstanding (HBU). (November 2011)</dc:description>
    <dc:description>This thesis provides some novel frameworks for learning human activities and for further classifying them into categories. This field of research has been largely studied by the computer vision community however there are still many drawbacks to solve. First, we have found few proposals in the literature for learning human activities from limited number of sequences. However, this learning is critical in several scenarios. For instance, in the initial stage after a system installation the capture of activity examples is time expensive and therefore, the learning with limited examples may accelerate the operational launch of the system. Moreover, examples for training abnormal behaviour are hardly obtainable and their learning may benefit from the same techniques. This problem is solved by some approaches, such as cross domain implementations or the use of invariant features, but they do not consider the specific scenario information which is useful for reducing the clutter and improving the results. Systems trained with scarce information face two main problems: on the one hand, the training process may suffer from numerical instabilities while estimating the model parameters; on the other hand, the model lacks of representative information coming from a diverse set of activity classes. We have dealt with these problems providing some novel approaches for learning human activities from one example, what is called a one-shot learning method. To do so, we have proposed generative approaches based on Hidden Markov Models as we need to learn each activity class from only one example. In addition, we have transferred information from external sources in order to introduce diverse information into the model. This thesis explains our proposals and shows how these methods achieve state-of-the-art results in three public datasets. Second, we have studied the recognition of human activities in unconstrained scenarios. In this case, the scenario may or may not be repeated in training and evaluation and therefore the clutter reduction previously mentioned does not happen. On the other hand, we can use any labelled video for training the system independently of the target scenario. This freedom allows the extraction of videos from the Internet dismissing the implicit constrains when training with limited examples. Having plenty of training examples both, generative and discriminative, methods can be used and by the time this thesis has been made the state-of-the-art has been achieved by discriminative ones. However, most of the methods usually fail when taking into consideration long-term information of the activities. This information is critical when comparing activities where the order of sub-actions is important, and may be useful in other comparisons as well. Thus, we have designed a framework that incorporates this information in a discriminative classifier. In addition, this method introduces some flexibility for sequence alignment, useful feature when the activity segmentation is not exact. Using this framework we have obtained state-of-the-art results in four challenging public datasets with unconstrained scenarios.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/57884</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Instituto de Investigación en Ingeniería de Aragón (I3A)</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/57884/files/TESIS-2016-219.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>inteligencia artificial</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>visión artificial</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>análisis de actividades</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>artificial intelligence</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>artificial vision</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>analysis of activities</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>The Understanding of Human Activities by Computer Vision Techniques</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TESIS</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
