<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Orús Sanclemente, Carlos</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>García Gamón, Carlos</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The increasing importance of technology and internet has provoked changes in the way music is consumed, providing consumers a wider variety of channels of music consumption. This undergraduate dissertation analyses the consumption behaviour of music streaming platforms, in particular YouTube and Spotify. More specifically, we analyse which features of streaming platforms are valued by users, and compare these features in YouTube and Spotify. In addition, the impact of these platforms on physical music consumption (physical formats purchases, attending live music events) is also examined. The results of two studies, consisting of a survey with consumers and an observation of music sales and streaming information, show that the presence of a great number of music content available, the possibility of listening to music everywhere, the platforms’ design and their usability are the features that users value the most. Finally, it has been empirically proved that streaming services have positive impact on CDs purchases.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77724</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77724/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-2497.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77724/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-2497_ANE.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Administración y Dirección de Empresas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>El comportamiento del consumidor multicanal en el sector de la música: El caso del streaming.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Multichannel Consumer Behaviour in the music sector: The streaming case.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
