<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Cea Mingueza, Pilar</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>Martínez de la Fuente, Jesús</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Ruiz Rincón, Silvia</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
    <dc:description>In this final master project model cell membranes of a mixture of 1, 2-dipalmitoyl-sn-glycero-3-phosphocholine (DPPC) and cholesterol were transferred onto mica substrates by Langmuir-Blodgett technique (LB) to mimic a real cell membrane. The high quality and chemical structure of the monolayers formed were confirmed by means of Atomic Force Microscopy (AFM) imaging and Contact Angle measurements. A study of the stability of the monolayer in liquid media considering the amphiphilic nature of the compounds was carried out, observing as the monolayer re-assembled into bilayer. This behaviour was explained by means of Force Spectroscopy (FS) studies with a noticeable increase in the breakthrough force values. Furthermore, the deposition of MNPs onto monolayer was carried out by LB in a successful way obtaining a well-covered distribution of MNPs with the final purpose of study the membrane response when it is exposed to alternating magnetic fields (Hyperthermia).</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/36781</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Química Física; Área de Química Física</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/36781/files/TAZ-TFM-2015-1094.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/36781/files/TAZ-TFM-2015-1094_ANE.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Materiales Nanoestructurados para Aplicaciones Nanotecnológicas (Nanostructured Materials for Nanotechnology Applications)</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Formation and characterization of model cell membranes and their interaction with Magnetic Nanoparticles</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
