<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Bravo Gil, Rafael</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Cisneros Pellejero, Natalia</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The purpose of this study is to analyse the context and situation of Algramar, a SME (small medium size enterprise) in the wine sector, under the principles of the organic winemaking. The main aim pursued on this dissertation is to support the company in the penetration of the online market, further describing the challenges it will face and the most consistent plan to maximize the performance efficiency. More specifically, we will provide Algramar with market information about the characteristics of the digital channel, and carry out a research on particular actions to build a consistent brand image online. We will hold on a compound of resources that will ease the path to attract traffic to our website, and turn it into actual sales. This plan involves search engine strategic knowledge, support of social media and mailing tracking techniques. The resulting conclusions will open a continuous improvement cycle to reach digital performance perfection.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77921</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Dirección de Márketing e Investigación de Mercados; Área de Comercialización e Investigación de Mercados</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77921/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-1954.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Administración y Dirección de Empresas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Digital Positioning Plan for Algramar Winery.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Digital Positioning Plan for Algramar Winery.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
