<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Kyratsis, Panagiotis</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>García Hernández, César</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Efkolidis, Nikolaos</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The influence of sustainability in product design and manufacturing processes can be considered from two different points of view: the design of sustainable products and the sustainable manufacturing of those products. Of course, a basic assumption for the aforementioned elements to be realized is the appropriate training and education for sustainability of the young designers and engineers.  In this research, sustainability has been applied to many fields, including design, manufacturing and education acting as an umbrella which covers all the three elements and has as the main target to promote sustainability. In today’s world, in which a considerable number of contrasting signs reveal that our society is currently contributing to the planet’s collapse, a new kind of engineer is needed, an engineer who is fully aware of what is going on in society and who has the skills to deal with aspects of sustainability. According to the literature review on the state-of-the-art associated to the subject, in the current research were developed tools and methodologies for the promotion of sustainability aspects that are related to product design, manufacturing and education.   &lt;br /&gt;Product Design&lt;br /&gt;The research work was based on a framework, which was built according to the direct communication between users and designers. There is a need for a cultural transformation, which can be focused on consumers and promote the needed behavioural change. Moreover there is a need for a cultural transformation on the role of designers and engineers to the product design process, with an aim to address sustainability as well as emerging priorities from societal to environmental challenges.  New tools and methodologies were generated, in order to promote sustainability to the users/citizens bringing them inside to the product design process, giving them the opportunity to be a vital part of it. &lt;br /&gt;Manufacturing&lt;br /&gt;Sustainable manufacturing faces new challenges for developing predictive models and optimization techniques in order to produce more products. The first part of the current is related to the drilling process and cutting tool technology. The creation of mathematical models focused on maximization of productivity and cost reduction by identifying crucial parameters and processes influencing manufacturing effectiveness. The second part of the current research is associated to the development of models used by CAD/ CAM that allow a rapid improvement and an efficient design and manufacture.&lt;br /&gt;Education&lt;br /&gt;The third aspect of the research is associated with the education related to sustainability.  The engineering students should develop sustainability competences such as critical thinking, systemic thinking, obtaining values consistent with the sustainability paradigm, except of just taking a course on sustainability, focus on the technological role of sustainability. Focus on that the current research was based on sustainable characteristics such as a) remote control freeware applications, b) share of valuable resources, c) distance learning methodology and d) active participation of the students.&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:description>&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77116</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Ingeniería de Diseño y Fabricación</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77116/files/TESIS-2019-054.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:subject>ingenieria de procesos</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Development of Sustainable Methodologies in Product Design, Manufacturing and Education</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TESIS</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
