<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Herrando Rodrigo, Mª Isabel</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Lázaro Pérez, Blanca María</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Abstract This study offers an analysis of interpersonality indicators, concretely self-mentions and engagement markers, in both academic and non-academic blogs belonging to four different disciplines, then consequently subjected to different conventions. In order to carry out this research, I have selected a corpus consisting of five blogs in ELF (English as a Lingua Franca) written by Spanish speakers, three of them non-academic – a cooking blog and two fashion blogs – and two of them academic – belonging to the fields of biology and psychology. The analysis of the results has been completed using Hyland’s metadiscourse paradigm (2005), exploring the frequency of appearance of self-mentions and engagement markers in each corpus. Resumen Este estudio pretende analizar los indicadores de interpersonalidad, más concretamente las auto-menciones del autor y las marcas de inclusión del lector, en varios blogs tanto académicos como no académicos pertenecientes a cuatro disciplinas diferentes, y por tanto sujetos a distintas convenciones. Para llevar a cabo el estudio, se ha seleccionado un corpus de cinco blogs en ELF (inglés como lengua franca) escritos por hablantes del español, tres de los cuales no son académicos – un blog sobre cocina y dos blogs sobre moda – y dos de los cuales sí son académicos – pertenecientes a los campos de la biología y la psicología. El análisis de los resultados se ha producido usando el paradigma de metadiscurso de Hyland (2005), observando la frecuencia de aparición de las auto-menciones y de las inclusiones del lector en cada uno de los corpus.&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85492</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85492/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-2054.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Interpersonality in ELF (Non)Academic Blogs: Self-mentions and Engagement Markers through Different Disciplines.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Interpersonality in ELF (Non)Academic Blogs: Self-mentions and Engagement Markers through Different Disciplines.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
