<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Vicente Rodríguez, Germán</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Pardos Aguilella, Pilar</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>ABSTRACT Introduction. Non-specific neck pain has an annual prevalence of 30-50% affections among the adult population, and is a high health expense. Objective. Study whether the working position affects the variables range of motion, neck disability index and presence of myofascial trigger points (PGMs). Material and methods: the study involved 75 subjects with non-specific neck pain, who were valued for upper and lower cervical range of motion (ROM), with the applications “Clinomete” and “Compass”, were applied the neck disability index (NDI) questionnaire and the presence of PGM of the upper trapeze, angular of the scapula, splenium of the neck, suboccipitals, occipitofrontal, orbicular, maseter, temporal and sternocleiomastoid by palpation. Results. In the comparative analysis, there were no statistically significant differences in the variables ROM, NDI and presence of PGMs accordind to the working position. There were no statistically significant strong correlations between the amount of PGMs and cervical ROM, as well as the amount of PGMs and neck disability index. Conclusions. The working position does not influence the variables ROM and NDI in patients with non-specific neck pain. No clear pattern could be established on the influence of PGMs on cervical ROM and NDI, so the results suggest that there may be more structures that influence cervical ROM and NDI in patients with non-specific neck pain. Therefore, more studies are needed to observe the influence of PGMs on cervical ROM and NDI. Key words. Non-specific neck pain, myofascial trigger point, range of motion, cervical spine&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/87890</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Fisiatría y Enfermería; Área de Educación Física y Deportiva</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/87890/files/TAZ-TFM-2019-153.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Evaluación y Entrenamiento Físico para la Salud</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Estudio descriptivo y comparativo de las diferencias entre el rango de movimiento cervical, el índice de discapacidad cervical y la presencia de puntos gatillos miofasciales en relación a la posición laboral presente.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Descriptive and comparative study of the differences between the range of cervical movement, the cervical disability index and the presence of myofascial trigger points in relation to the present work position</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
