<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Allué Baelo, Sonia</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Rodrigo Alonso, Pilar</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Women have historically been undervalued compared to men and, on numerous occasions, little credit has been given to what they said or what they thought or did. This prejudice of female inferiority may partly explain why if, at some point, a woman was raped, the blame fell on her: she had not put enough resistance, she was lying or, deep down, she wanted to be raped. These were common arguments levelled against raped women at the beginning of the last century. For this reason, silence was a common response for raped women: they had much to lose if people around found out. Since then, this way of thinking has progressively evolved and women have been acquiring more rights. It is my contention to analyse the way rape is depicted in the already finished and successful television series Downton Abbey, and its controversial reception when the specific episodes were released in 2013. In spite of being acclaimed on several occasions for its historical rigor and applauded by both critics and the public, the rape of one of the most beloved character in 1922 did not accurately reflect what would have been a "normal" reaction at the time to an event like this nor the way people would act nowadays. This controversial depiction and apparent lack of historical accuracy can only be accounted for after studying the treatment of raped women in the early 20th century, the evolution of society’s way of thinking and, focusing on the series, the behaviour of some characters after knowing about the rape.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75204</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75204/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-1455.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>A Change of Mentality Over a Century: Rape and the Controversy Generated in Downton Abbey</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">A Change of Mentality Over a Century: Rape and the Controversy Generated in Downton Abbey</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
