<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Martínez Pérez, Concepción</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>Cogolludo Agustín, José Ignacio</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Blasco García, Rubén</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Right-angled Artin groups form an interesting family of groups both from an&lt;br /&gt;algebraic and a topological point of view. There are a lot of well-known properties&lt;br /&gt;of right-angled Artin groups: for example they are poly-free, locally&lt;br /&gt;indicable, right orderable and residually finite. Besides, also many important&lt;br /&gt;problems are well understood for these groups such as the word problem, the&lt;br /&gt;rigidity problem, Serre's question or the K(pi, 1) conjecture.&lt;br /&gt;In this thesis, we will study some of these properties for a bigger and&lt;br /&gt;interesting subfamily of Artin groups: even Artin groups. We generalize&lt;br /&gt;many of these properties either for even Artin groups in full genarility or for&lt;br /&gt;some big and interesting subfamilies.&lt;br /&gt;In particular, we prove that even Artin groups of FC type and large even&lt;br /&gt;Artin groups are poly-free (which, as we will see, implies that they are also&lt;br /&gt;locally indicable and right orderable) and that even Artin groups of FC type&lt;br /&gt;and general Artin groups based on trees are residually finite. Finally, we&lt;br /&gt;answer Serre's question for the whole family of even Artin groups.&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:description>&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/87133</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Matemáticas</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/87133/files/TESIS-2020-020.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:subject>grupos generalidades</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>geometria algebraica</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Even Artin Groups</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TESIS</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
