<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Laclaustra Gimeno, Martín</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Ordóñez Rubio, Beatriz</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Entre los trabajadores de una factoria,  208 casos indicentes de enfermedad cardiovascular entre 1981 y 2005 fueron emparejados por edad con 2080 trabajadores sanos visitados de forma rutinaria entre 2004-2005. El sindrome metabolico fue definido por los criterios revisados de la definición ATP-III (2005).  El SM estaba fuertemente asociado con la enfermedad cardiovascular (OR=4-03; 95%CI2.98,5.45) y el riesgo parece todo ser explicado por los componenetes de SM (OR=0.84, p=0.54).  la Odds ratio del efecto independiente de cada uno de los criterios diagnosticos de SM fue: hipertrigliceridemia  (OR=3.39, p&lt;0.001), hiperglucemia(OR=2,7,p&lt;0.001), HDL colesterol bajo (OR=2,35, p&lt;0.001), hipertension (OR=1,49,p=0,016) y sobrepeso (OR 1,07,p=0.678).</dc:description>
    <dc:description>Amongs the workers of a factory, 208 incident cases of cardiac heart disease (CHD) between 1981 and 2005 were age matched with 2080 healthy workers visited routinely in 2004-2005. The metabolic syndrome (MetS) was characterized with modified criteria of the revised ATP-III definition (2005). MetS was strongly associated with CHD (OR=4-03; 95%CI2.98,5.45) and the risk increase seems to be fully explained by Met S components (OR=0.84, p=0.54 after adjustment). Odds ratios for the independent effects of the diagnostic criteria were: hyperglyceridemia (OR=3.39, p&amp;lt;0.001), hyperglcemia (OR=2,7,p&amp;lt;0.001), low HDL-cholesterol (OR=2,35, p&amp;lt;0.001), hypertension (OR=1,49,p=0,016) and overweight (OR 1,07,p=0.678).</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/4553</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Medicina, Psiquiatría y Dermatología</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/4553/files/TESIS-2010-028.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Sindrome metabolico</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>cardiopatia isquemica</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Metabolic syndrome</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>coronary heart disease</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Asociación de los distintos componentes de síndrome metabólico y riesgo de cardiopatía isquémica en población laboral española</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TESIS</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
