<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Yebra Pertusa, José María</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Puértolas Torres, Ana</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>ABSTRACT The communicative competence, stated by the LOMCE curriculum as one of the main points to develop during secondary education, understands languages as more than tools for transaction, considering them as a necessary means to reach understanding among people. This implication sets the basis to affirm that language learning is key so as to improve social cohesion, particularly busting stereotypes and sharing feelings and experiences with others. Taking this idea into account, the present “Trabajo de Fin de Máster” researches on how introducing aspects related to the LGBT+ community in the EFL classroom in secondary education may help students to discuss, write, listen to and read about gender identity and thus fight the fear that leads to homophobic and transphobic aggressions, including physical and verbal abuse, or rejection within the school environment as it was stated by a survey to both teachers and students. With the aim to fight this form of bullying, several lessons are proposed, together with a reflection on those that could be implemented on a real school context during my teaching in placement, followed by a commentary on how students reacted to them and on how their own reflection also affected the manner in which they perceived the LGBT+ collective.   RESUMEN La competencia comunicativa, establecida por el currículum de la LOMCE como uno de los principales puntos a desarrollar durante la educación secundaria, comprende el lenguaje como algo más que una herramienta de transacción, considerándolo un vehículo necesario para permitir el entendimiento entre las personas. Esta implicación sienta las bases para considerar que el aprendizaje de una lengua es básico para mejorar la cohesión social: desmintiendo estereotipos y compartiendo sensaciones y experiencias con los demás. Teniendo en cuenta esta idea, el presente Trabajo de Fin de Máster investiga cómo el hecho de introducir aspectos relacionados con el colectivo LGBT+ puede ayudar a los estudiantes a debatir, escribir, escuchar y leer sobre temas relacionados con la identidad de género teniendo como meta combatir los miedos que llevan a la homofobia y la transfobia, incluyendo agresiones físicas y verbales, así como rechazo en el entorno escolar tal y como describieron las encuestas realizadas a profesores y alumnos. Así pues, con la intención de luchar contra este tipo de acoso, este trabajo presenta una serie de lecciones, así como una reflexión acerca de aquellas que pudieron ser implementadas durante la parte práctica del máster, junto con un comentario sobre las reacciones de los estudiantes a las mismas, que muestra cómo su propia reflexión también cambió su manera de percibir el colectivo LGBT+.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77462</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77462/files/TAZ-TFM-2018-351.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Somewhere over the classroom: how to introduce lgtb+ visibility on second language teaching materials</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Somewhere over the classroom: how to introduce lgtb+ visibility on second language teaching materials</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
