<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Herrero Granado, María Dolores</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Benedi Lamarca, Vanessa</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The main objective of this Final Degree Dissertation will be to analyse the novel Two Years, Eight Months and Twenty-Eight Nights by Salman Rushdie. A good example of the literary movement known as magic realism, it illustrates what the great majority of critics consider to be the main characteristic of this sort of texts: the gradual insertion of the magic element onto the apparently realist text until the total superposition/overlapping of reality and fiction takes place. This is here done in order to represent the rationalism/religion binary and, more precisely, to denounce the rejection of reason in order to impose religious fanaticism, which is currently booming in certain parts of the world. The shocking and strange lack of gravity with which the novel beings will progressively dovetail into a whole fantastic world, which will put into question, not only the rationalism on which our modern world is based, but also the mere relevance and existence of it. By means of the use of magic realism, the novel manages, in the first place, to send some warning about the potential danger of religious fanaticism taking control of the world and, secondly, to show that fiction can be a very useful tool/vehicle to bring to the surface the contradictions of the real world.&lt;br /&gt;Resumen&lt;br /&gt;El objetivo principal de este Trabajo de Fin de Grado será analizar la novela Two Years, Eight Months and Twenty-Eight Nights, de Salman Rushdie, como un buen ejemplo del movimiento literario conocido como realismo mágico, ya que ilustra lo que la mayoría de críticos consideran como la característica principal de este tipo de textos, a saber: la introducción gradual del elemento mágico en una narración aparentemente realista hasta dar lugar al solapamiento/ superposición total de realidad y fantasía. Todo ello, en este caso, en aras a representar el binarismo racionalismo/religión, y más en concreto a cuestionar el abandono del primero con el objetivo de imponer el fanatismo religioso, tan en auge hoy en día en ciertas partes del mundo. La inicial y chocante falta de gravedad con la que la novela comienza dará paulatinamente lugar a todo un mundo fantástico, que no sólo pone en tela de juicio el racionalismo sobre el que supuestamente se basa el mundo moderno, sino también la propia relevancia y existencia de este. A través del uso del realismo mágico la novela en cuestión consigue, no solo advertir acerca del peligro que supondría que el fanatismo religioso acabara controlando el mundo, sino también demostrar que la ficción puede ser un instrumento muy útil para poner de relieve las contradicciones del mundo real.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85155</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85155/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-3143.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Faith versus Reason as Reflected in Salman Rushdie´s Two Years, Eitgh Months and Twenty-Eight Nights.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Faith versus Reason as Reflected in Salman Rushdie´s Two Years, Eitgh Months and Twenty-Eight Nights.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
