<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Orna Montesinos, Concepción</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Aliana Cordeiro, Marta</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2020</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This project will show an analytic study of five Disney films (Snow White, The Sleeping Beauty, Mulan, Tangled and Frozen) in terms of gender roles. The films have been selected because of their relevance for the society and even more for the themes to analyze. Besides, the movies are separated in time, relating to their performance, in order to remark Disney company evolution in terms of gender roles. As it has been mentioned, the main aim of this project is studying the gender roles in different films and in order to achieve this aim, different aspects such as physical appearance, personality and roles in the films of both male and female characters have been analyzed. The analysis will highlight that even modern films show a stereotyped view of gender which suggests many stereotypes. The main consequence of this fact is that the whole society and even more children watch this kind of films in a non-critical view and the most important ideas generated by the films stick on people’s mind, contributing to the maintenance of ancient gender roles and stereotypes in our current and future societies.&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/95159</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/95159/files/TAZ-TFG-2020-3121.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Magisterio en Educación Primaria</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Un análisis de los roles de género en las películas de Disney: Desde Blancanieves (1941) hasta Frozen (2013)</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">An analysis of gender roles in Disney films: From Snow White (1941) to Frozen (2013)</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
