<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Oliete Aldea, Elena</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Romeo Grant, Tania</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The Best Exotic Marigold Hotel and The Second Best Exotic Marigold Hotel, two ‘mainstream feel-good movies’ which could seem aimed at providing entertainment and comfort in the economic crisis context of western societies, are analysed from a cultural viewpoint, within the historical conjuncture of the moment, providing a more complex discourse about identity and postcolonial relationships.&lt;br /&gt;A textual and cultural analysis of these two movies is carried out, using film and cultural studies as a methodological approach, focusing on the historical moment in which they take place. Some characters are also analysed considering the socioeconomic context the films are set in, paying attention to representation and identity from a postcolonial perspective. On the one hand, how the Marigold Hotel films reflect the post 2008 financial crisis / pre-Brexit moment when they were filmed and denounce the effects of the economic instability produced by these phenomena will be demonstrated. And, on the other hand, how they aim to portray a positive approach to issues such as ageing, ethnicity, sexuality and gender, but simultaneously manage to replicate postcolonial stereotyped representations of the Other, reminiscent of Britain’s imperial past, whose values are largely present in the discourses of the country’s neoliberal governments, present and past. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Resumen.&lt;br /&gt;El exótico Hotel Marigold y El nuevo exótico Hotel Marigold, dos películas de comedia ligera para el público general que podrían parecer pensadas para entretener y confortar en la situación de crisis económica de las sociedades occidentales, se analizan desde un punto de vista cultural, dentro de la coyuntura histórica del momento, ofreciendo un discurso más complejo sobre identidad y relaciones postcoloniales. Se realiza un análisis textual y cultural de estas dos películas, utilizando teorías cinematográficas y culturales como enfoque metodológico, tomando en consideración el momento histórico en el que ocurren. También se analizan algunos personajes teniendo en cuenta el contexto socioeconómico en el que se encuentran las películas, prestando atención a la representación y la identidad desde una perspectiva postcolonial. Por un lado, se demostrará cómo las películas del Hotel Marigold reflejan el momento posterior a la crisis financiera del 2008 / pre-Brexit cuando fueron filmadas y denuncian los efectos de la inestabilidad económica producida por estos fenómenos. Y, por otro lado, cómo pretenden retratar positivamente cuestiones como el envejecimiento, la etnicidad, la sexualidad y el género, pero al mismo tiempo logran replicar representaciones estereotipadas postcoloniales del Otro, que recuerdan al pasado imperial de Gran Bretaña, cuyos valores están en gran parte presentes en los discursos de los gobiernos neoliberales del país, presentes y pasados. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/87875</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/87875/files/TAZ-TFM-2019-1271.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Estudios Avanzados de Literatura y Cine en Lengua Inglesa</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Análisis postcolonial de las películas del Hotel Marigold en el contexto de pre-Brexit.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The Marigold Hotel Films: A Postcolonial Analysis in a Pre-Brexit Context.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
