<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Moreno Vega, Yamir</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Báez Martín, Miguel</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The adaptation of Mycobacterium tuberculosis to the human immune system is a near-perfect paradigm of a host-pathogen relationship. In the process of evolution, it has acquired the ability to evade immune-mediated clearance and to establish latent or progressive infection through a coordinated program of immune evasion strategies. A recent observation in the field is that the large majority of M. tuberculosis epitopes which interact with the human adaptive immune system are highly conserved. This observation suggests that, apart from immune evasion strategies, M. tuberculosis could benefit from recognition by T cells and certain immune responses. The significance of these findings isn’t only important to understand pathogenesis, as it provides crucial information regarding the development of more effective new vaccines based on attenuated mycobacterial strains. This work aims to study the hypothesis that M. tuberculosis benefits from T cell recognition and its relation with the metabolic and genetic responses that the bacteria employ to confront macrophage-induced stress. By drawing upon a previously described PPI network, together with the meta-analysis of the gene expression datasets available at the Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO) database, it has been possible to construct a Multiplex network composed of a selection of stresses resembling the different in-vivo conditions that characterize the phagosome environment. This singular methodology provides an excellent framework to study the variations of the gene expression profiles that represent the bacterial stress-responses. However, until now it hadn’t been used to study the unexpected correlation between gene expression and epitope conservation, a remarkable characteristic of M. tuberculosis that can only be comprehended under the light of evolution.  The results from the statistical analysis of the Multiplex network and the enrichment analysis of the stress layers revealed that the antigenic factors from M. tuberculosis interact more actively with the rest of components of the network. In addition, their generic-stress response expression patterns support the hypothesis that MTB benefits from the immunological events that take place after T cell recognition. Surprisingly, the Regions of Difference that defines the different members of the M. tuberculosis Complex were significantly enriched in some relevant stress conditions. The remarkable finding that ESAT-6 is the main antigenic family expressed under all situations reflect its critical role as key virulence elements of the disease. Unexpectedly, other antigenic families related like the secretion systems ESX-1 &amp; 3 showed similar relevance and presence in the network.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/76255</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Bioquímica y Biología Molecular y Celular; Área de Bioquímica y Biología Molecular</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/76255/files/TAZ-TFM-2018-762.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Biotecnología Cuantitativa</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Un abordaje de redes multicapa para estudiar las respuestas de M. tuberculosis frente al estrés inducido in-vitro y su relación con la conservación de epítopos</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">A Multiplex network approach to study the responses of M. tuberculosis to in-vitro induced stress and its relation with epitope conservation</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
