<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Ugarte Vilumbrales, Luis</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>Villacampa Gutiérrez, Raquel</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Latorre Larrodé, Adela</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2016</dc:date>
    <dc:description>In this thesis we focus our attention on a special class of compact manifolds, known as nilmanifolds, and study their complex geometry up to (real) dimension eight.  Our main objectives are to construct all invariant complex structures on such spaces, analyze several cohomological aspects in complex dimension 3, and investigate new geometric structures and Hermitian metrics which arise in complex dimension 4. We next give a short description of each chapter. Chapter 1 is introductory. We review the basic concepts that will be used along this work and fix the notation.  In Chapter 2 we investigate cohomological properties of 6-dimensional nilmanifolds with invariant complex structure. First, we study the behaviour under holomorphic deformation of some properties related to the d-dbar-lemma condition that can be defined in terms of the Bott-Chern cohomology groups. Then, we focus on the problem of cohomological decomposition, paying particular attention to the real decomposition at the second stage. Chapter 3 is devoted to the problem of constructing invariant complex structures on nilmanifolds of arbitrary dimension 2n. More concretely, we provide an strategy to find any complex structure J on any 2n-dimensional nilpotent Lie algebra without the need of knowing the involved algebras in advance. Indeed, two methods are introduced according to the degree of nilpotency of the complex structure J to be constructed. The combination of these two approaches allows to construct invariant complex structures on nilmanifolds of any even dimension. As an application, we recover the classification of complex structures on nilpotent Lie algebras of dimensions four and six. We also start the study of dimension eight, which is completed in Chapter 4. As a consequence, we parametrize every 8-dimensional nilmanifold endowed with an invariant complex structure. The previous classification result is used in Chapter 5 with the aim of analyzing some geometric structures that do not appear in dimensions 4 and 6. On the one hand, we concentrate on Hermitian metrics, paying attention to the similarities and differences among SKT, astheno-Kähler, and generalized Gauduchon metrics. On the other hand, we study holomorphic symplectic and pseudo-Kähler structures.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>En esta tesis centramos nuestra atención en una clase especial de variedades compactas, conocidas como nilvariedades, y estudiar su geometría compleja hasta (real) dimensión ocho. Nuestros principales objetivos son la construcción de todas las estructuras complejas invariantes en tales espacios, analizar varios aspectos cohomológicos en dimensión compleja 3 e investigar nuevas estructuras geométricas y las métricas hermitianos que surgen en la dimensión compleja 4. A continuación damos una breve descripción de cada capítulo. El capítulo 1 es introductorio. Se revisan los conceptos básicos que se utilizarán a lo largo de este trabajo y fijan la notación. En el capítulo 2 se investigan las propiedades de cohomológicas nilvariedades 6 dimensiones con estructura compleja invariante. En primer lugar, se estudia el comportamiento bajo deformación olomorfa de algunas propiedades relacionadas con la condición d-dbar-lema que se puede definir en términos de los grupos de cohomología Bott-Chern. A continuación, nos centramos en el problema de la descomposición cohomológica, prestando especial atención a la descomposición real en la segunda etapa. El capítulo 3 está dedicado al problema de construir estructuras complejas invariantes en nilvariedades de 2ª dimensión arbitraria. Más concretamente, proporcionamos una estrategia para encontrar cualquier complejo J estructura en cualquier álgebra de Lie nilpotente 2n dimensiones sin la necesidad de conocer las álgebras involucradas con antelación. De hecho, para ser construida, se introducen dos métodos de acuerdo con el grado de nilpotencia de la compleja estructura J. La combinación de estos dos enfoques permite construir estructuras complejas invariantes en nilvariedades de cualquier dimensión. Como una aplicación, recuperamos la clasificación de las estructuras complejas de álgebras de Lie nilpotente de dimensiones cuatro y seis. También comenzamos el estudio de la dimensión ocho, que se completa en el capítulo 4. Como consecuencia de ello, parametrizamos cada nilmanifold 8-dimensional dotado de una estructura compleja invariante. El resultado de la clasificación anterior se utiliza en el capítulo 5, con el objetivo de analizar algunas estructuras geométricas que no aparecen en las dimensiones 4 y 6. Por un lado, nos concentramos en las métricas hermitianas, prestando atención a las similitudes y diferencias entre SKT, astheno- Kähler, y la métrica Gauduchon generalizadas. Por otro lado, se estudian las estructuras simplécticas y pseudo-Kähler holomorfas.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/56712</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Matemáticas</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/56712/files/TESIS-2016-194.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>geometría diferencial</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>variedades complejas</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>differential geometry</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>complex varieties</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Geometry of nilmanifolds with invariant complex structure</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TESIS</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
