<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Almazán Tomás, Vicente David</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Largo Pérez, Lara</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>En este trabajo hablaremos sobre la figura de Hayao Miyazaki en el cine  de animación. Realizando una introducción sobre la animación previa  antes del estudio Ghibli en Japón, una biografía del director y  analizaremos las fases del estudio que el mismo fundo con la ayuda de  Takahata. Finalmente abordaremos el tema central de nuestro trabajo, el  estudio de los temas relevantes en sus películas cómo una manera de  concienciar al público del ecologismo, el feminismo y el pacifismo,  principalmente.  In this work we will speak on Hayao Miyazaki's figure in the cinema of  animation. Making and introduction to the previous animation before the  Ghibli’s studio in Japan, a biography of the director and we will  analyze the phases of the study that he himself founded with the help of  Takahata. Finally we will study the central topic of our work, the  relevant topics in his movies how a way of arousing the public of the  environmentalism, the feminism and the pacifism, principally.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75152</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Historia del Arte</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75152/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-1967.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75152/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-1967_ANE.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Historia del Arte</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>El cine de animación de Hayao Miyazaki</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The animation cinema of Hayao Miyazaki</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
