<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Pellicer Ortín, Silvia</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Suárez Coro, María Alejandra</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This dissertation seeks to prove that a literary project about women writers and feminism can help a group of students in 2nd year of ESO to develop their key competences, as well as their communicative competence, at the same time they work on curricular themes and values such as gender awareness and equality. With this study, I also intend to demonstrate that students’ interest in literature and poetry, which is the chosen genre, can increase thanks to a literary project. In order to conduct this research, I reviewed the most important literature on Second Language Acquisition (SLA), Communicative Language Teaching (CLT), Project-Based Learning (PBL) and Project-Based Language Learning (PBLL), together with works about the use of literature in the EFL classroom, in order to lay the theoretical foundations of this work. Then, I designed some tools so as to select literary texts appropriate for the students’ level. Next, I conducted a pre-test to evaluate their needs and level. Afterwards, I designed the project following the aforementioned theoretical framework, as well as the curricular framework that governs the teaching of English as a Foreign Language (EFL) in Spain. The implementation of this project, together with a post-test, revealed that the students’ communicative competence and gender awareness actually improved, as they successfully completed the project’s challenge and proved to have learnt about feminism by communicating in English. Finally, this study has also uncovered some issues related to the use of literature in the EFL classroom, such as the time necessary to conduct a literary project successfully, which may help other teachers implement this type of project.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86680</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86680/files/TAZ-TFM-2019-712.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Literature and PBLL in the EFL Secondary Education Classroom: A Literary Project about Women Writers</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Literature and PBLL in the EFL Secondary Education Classroom: A Literary Project about Women Writers</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
