<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Tarancón de Francisco, Juan Antonio</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Villa Guzmán-Moliner, Elisa</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Abstract My dissertation project consists in an analysis of the film WALL-E from an environmental perspective. I argue that WALL-E is, among other things, a call to care for the environment at a time when climate change and environmental policies have made the destruction of planet Earth a real threat. To get a better sense of the ways the film engages with the challenges posed by our treatment of the environment during the last decades, I first consider the political context and, in particular the policies pursued by the different US Governments in relation to climate change. Then, I place WALL-E within the framework of film history and consider how it relates to animation cinema in general and the different policies of the two production companies that made film, Walt Disney and Pixar, in particular. My analysis focuses on two scenes. In the first one, I pursue questions about the manipulation of film genres, being the musical genre the most important one. In the second one, I consider the discourse on technology put together by the film and how it urges the viewer to relate it with the course our society has taken and its links with the environment. Finally, I try to argue the importance of films that, like WALL-E, send the message that we should take care of the environment.  Resumen Mi TFG contiene un análisis de la película WALL-E desde un punto de vista medioambiental que transmite a diferentes tipos de público el mensaje de cuidar el medio ambiente para no acabar destruyendo el planeta Tierra. Para llevarlo a cabo he realizado una contextualización política haciendo hincapié en las políticas medioambientales de los diferentes gobiernos de EEUU así como otra contextualización acerca del cine de animación, siendo las compañías Walt Disney y Pixar las protagonistas. Este análisis se centra en dos escenas de la película WALL-E. En la primera escena destaco la combinación de diferentes géneros cinematográficos considerando el género musical el más importante. En la segunda escena he desarrollado el tema de la tecnología presente en WALL-E y el mensaje medioambiental que ésta transmite, cuidar del medioambiente.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/76693</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/76693/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-3315.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>"I Don't Want to Survive, I Want to Live": WALL-E and the Environment</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">"I Don't Want to Survive, I Want to Live": WALL-E and the Environment</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
