<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Azcona Montoliu, María del Mar</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Wood Borque, Paula</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>ABSTRACT This dissertation explores the ambiguous portrayal of the character Beatrix Kiddo as a feminist icon in Quentin Tarantino’s films Kill Bill Vol. 1 and Kill Bill Vol. 2 (2003-2004). The main contention of this essay is that even if Beatrix was regarded as a feminist figure by the critics at the time of the films’ release, there are many ambiguities regarding the character that question this approach. This essay starts with an introduction to the different feminist waves and the action film genre in order to provide a context for the reading of the films that follows. For the analysis of the films I offer a section on the portrayal of female characters in Quentin Tarantino’s films and then I focus on three basic features present in both of them – identity, (lack of) sorority and motherhood – and the contrasting information that they offer on the character. As I will argue, Beatrix Kiddo is a character full of ambivalence and she might not be the feminist icon she appears to be at first.  RESUMEN Este trabajo de fin de grado analiza la ambigüedad en la representación del personaje Beatrix Kiddo como icono feminista en las películas de Quentin Tarantino Kill Bill Vol. 1 y Kill Bill Vol. 2 (2003-2004). El argumento principal de este trabajo es que incluso si los críticos consideraban a Beatrix una figura feminista cuando las películas fueron estrenadas, hay muchas ambigüedades con respecto a este personaje que cuestionan este enfoque. Este ensayo comienza con una introducción sobre los distintos movimientos feministas y el cine de acción para proporcionar un contexto para el análisis de las películas que le sigue. Para el análisis ofrezco una sección sobre la representación de los personajes femeninos en las películas de Quentin Tarantino y después me centro en tres elementos básicos que están presentes en las dos – identidad, (falta de) sororidad y maternidad – y la información contrastante que presentan sobre el personaje. Como razonaré en este trabajo, Beatrix Kiddo es un personaje lleno de ambivalencias y puede que no sea el icono feminista que aparenta ser en un principio.&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85486</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85486/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-2063.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>"She's a little blood-spattered angel": The portrayal of Beatrix Kiddo in Kill Bill (2003-2004).</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">"She's a little blood-spattered angel": The portrayal of Beatrix Kiddo in Kill Bill (2003-2004).</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
