<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Castro Escario, Elisenda</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Lupón Calvete, Sara.</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The main purpose of the present dissertation is to analyze the benefits of gamification, cooperation and cultural knowledge in the teaching of EFL in Secondary Education. These three pivotal tenets were considered in the design of the Lesson Plan as they were coherent with the results obtained from classroom observation and reflection and from two different surveys done among students. Consequently, the Unit, entitled Around the World in 6 Days, consists of a learning path of six lessons around five different countries focused on their main cultural descriptors with the aim of expanding students' intercultural identity and strengthening values such as tolerance and respect for diversity. Having in mind both CLT and curriculum framework, the proposal was also conceived to boost various motivational levels and meant to develop Students’ academic and personal growth to promote a lifelong learning. Furthermore, the use of ICTs, authentic materials, creative and interactional tasks and the development of the seven keys competences was emphasized while the cognitive processes were worked from the less complex to the more complex, being efficiency in communication the ultimate goal .</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77338</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77338/files/TAZ-TFM-2018-1103.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>A proposal for 4th year e.s.o students to explore the cultural journey of learning: around the world in 6 days.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">A proposal for 4th year e.s.o students to explore the cultural journey of learning: around the world in 6 days.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
