<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Luzón Marco, María José</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Villares Maldonado, Rosana</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The main purpose of this dissertation is to design and evaluate materials from an English as Lingua Franca perspective to teach English in secondary education. Firstly, the dissertation introduces the definition and main characteristics of English as Lingua Franca, paying special attention to the development of the intercultural competence and the intercultural communicative competence. The methodology selected to teach English is one practice of the Communicative Language Teaching Approach, the project-based learning, so students from 4th year of ESO make an intercultural project investigating and comparing target and home cultures. Finally, after commenting on the assessment of both the students’ projects and the project itself, it can be said that presenting intercultural competence through project work is a good way to introduce this aspect of the communicative competence (democratic value/key competence). At the same time, students experience many of the advantages of the Communicative Language Teaching approach that can be found in the LOE and LOMCE Aragonese Curriculum.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/36854</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/36854/files/TAZ-TFM-2015-369.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Project Work as a Tool to Develop Intercultural Competence from an ELF Perspective in Secondary Education</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
