<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Irusta Alderete, Silvia</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Coba Daza, Jorge Sebastián</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Electrospinning is a versatile technique that uses an electrical charge to produce very fine&lt;br /&gt;fibers from a polymeric solution. It has very high potential to be applied in different fields as&lt;br /&gt;in energy storage, in medicine, in cosmetics and in catalysis. Electrospinning is cost effective,&lt;br /&gt;reproducible and it can produce long and continuous nanofibers. Polymers such polyamides,&lt;br /&gt;polyalcohol and PVP among others, can be easily electrospun. The use of inorganic&lt;br /&gt;nanofibers obtained from template-based electrospun polymers is increasing because their&lt;br /&gt;performance in different applications due to the high surface to volume ratio.&lt;br /&gt;In this work three different nanofibers (Ce2O/NiO, CeO2/NiO/MgO and TiO2-doped-Fe2O3&lt;br /&gt;NP) were synthesized trough electrospinning process followed by a calcination process. The&lt;br /&gt;processing conditions such as voltage applied and feed rate in the electrospinning process&lt;br /&gt;were studied to find the best conditions for uniform fibers production. The calcination&lt;br /&gt;process was performed to completely oxidize the organic PVP present and promote the&lt;br /&gt;growth of the oxide nanoparticles that form the nanofiber.&lt;br /&gt;Characterization techniques such as scanning electron microscopy (SEM), energy dispersive&lt;br /&gt;X-ray spectroscopy (EDX), transmission electron microscopy (TEM), X-ray diffraction&lt;br /&gt;(XRD), X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), thermogravimetric analysis (TGA),&lt;br /&gt;microwave plasma-atomic emission spectroscopy (MP-AES), temperature programmed&lt;br /&gt;reduction (TPR), dynamic light scattering (DLS) and UV-vis spectroscopy were used to&lt;br /&gt;study the morphology, chemical and crystal characteristics of the samples. This work&lt;br /&gt;discusses the possibility to future use of the different synthesized nanofibers in the&lt;br /&gt;applications in catalysis for the CO2 methanation reaction (CeO2/NiO and CeO2/NiO/MgO&lt;br /&gt;nanofibers) and the water pollutants removal (TiO2-dop-Fe2O3 NP)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86839</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Ingeniería Química y Tecnologías del Medio Ambiente; Área de Tecnologías del Medio Ambiente</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86839/files/TAZ-TFM-2019-275.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster en Materiales Nanoestructurados para Aplicaciones Nanotecnológicas (Nanostructured Materials for Nanotechnology Applications)</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Síntesis y caracterización de fibras de óxidos a través de electrospinning para aplicaciones en catálisis</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Synthesis and characterization of electrospun oxide fibers for catalytic applications</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
