<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Mur Dueñas, Pilar</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Trell Hernández, Alexandra Carlota</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The aim of this dissertation is to design and propose an educational blog in which the communication between the student and the teacher leads to effective assessment of EFL oral performance which could be used in Spanish secondary schools. I propose making use of ICTs to assess students and make them responsible of their own learning by integrating technology. In this respect, I would not conduct grammatical tests at the end of term or at the end of year. I believe students must be taught new assessment and evaluation processes. Teachers have to explain that not having a final test does not mean that expectations or class demands are going to be lower. Teachers must also motivate their students, provide constant feedback and design personalised assessment plans.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/8017</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/8017/files/TAZ-TFM-2012-143.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Effective asssessment of EFL oral performance in Spanish secondary schools: a proposal</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
