<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Hornero Corisco, Ana María</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Pérez Escusa, Sara</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2020</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Abstract&lt;br /&gt;This dissertation aims to analyze the Spanish translation of The Office (US) in order to demonstrate how it manipulates the portrayal of Michael Scott’s personality. The analysis is based on Zabalbeascoa’s classification of jokes and Molina and Hurtado’s classification of translation techniques. The use of a two-layered comedy and a large amount of wordplay makes this show particularly difficult to translate. Thus, this paper will follow Castro’s steps to explain how he translated it. The analysis reveals that by gradually losing Michael’s charm and wittiness in the target text, the final product that reaches the target audience is slightly changed and they will never get to know the original Michael Scott.&lt;br /&gt;Resumen&lt;br /&gt;Este trabajo tiene como objetivo analizar la traducción al español de la versión americana de The Office para demostrar cómo esta manipula la personalidad de Michael Scott. El análisis está basado en la clasificación de chistes de Zabalbeascoa y en la clasificación de técnicas de traducción de Molina y Hurtado, y este trabajo sigue los pasos que tomó Castro al traducir la serie. La traducción de esta serie es particularmente compleja, ya que la versión original cuenta con muchos juegos de palabras y con una comedia bastante peculiar, llena de dobles sentidos. El análisis muestra que en la versión traducida se va perdiendo la carisma y el ingenio de Michael Scott hasta el punto de que el producto que llega a la audiencia española está ligeramente cambiado y esta audiencia nunca podrá conocer al verdadero Michael Scott. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94662</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94662/files/TAZ-TFG-2020-2391.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Dubbed to Absurdity: Michael Scott’s Change of Personality in The Office's Spanish Translation.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Dubbed to Absurdity: Michael Scott’s Change of Personality in The Office's Spanish Translation.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
