<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Murillo Ornat, Silvia</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Cubillo Gonzalo, Guillermo</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2020</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Abstract:&lt;br /&gt;Spanish secondary education is increasingly embracing a bilingual methodology that enables the learning of content subjects through the English language. Nevertheless, English as a foreign language teaching tends to make use of the students’ mother tongue and the use of the first language plays a controversial role which has been discussed throughout the history of second language acquisition. This dissertation focuses on the students and teachers’ attitudes towards the use of Spanish as a resource during the process of learning English. More concretely, it aims to show how students and teachers perceive that the sporadic use of Spanish in the secondary-education EFL classroom can be beneficial for learning English. For this purpose, two questionnaires were designed—one for teachers and one for students— and were completed accordingly by students and teachers in order to contribute with new insights and new research findings for the study of this subject matter. The results allow a detailed analysis about the different points of view by the participants. Both teachers and students consider the role of Spanish may be helpful for the productivity of learning English in the classroom.&lt;br /&gt;Resumen:&lt;br /&gt;La educación secundaria obligatoria en España cada vez se está adaptando más a un modelo bilingüe basado en el aprendizaje de otras materias a través del inglés como vehículo de comunicación. La enseñanza del inglés como lengua extranjera es un aprendizaje en el que se suele recurrir al uso de la lengua materna de los alumnos. Sin embargo, esta práctica ha generado mucha controversia a lo largo de la historia de la adquisición de un segundo idioma. Por ello este trabajo se centra en analizar las preferencias de los estudiantes y profesores ante el uso del español como recurso durante el proceso de aprendizaje del inglés. En concreto, el objetivo de este trabajo es demostrar cómo perciben los estudiantes y profesores que el uso esporádico del español en las clases de inglés en secundaria pueda favorecer el aprendizaje de la lengua meta. Para ello, se diseñaron dos cuestionarios que fueron completados por el alumnado y el profesorado respectivamente, con el objeto de aportar nuevos conocimientos sobre el estudio de este tema. Los resultados permiten obtener un amplio análisis con información detallada sobre los distintos puntos de vista de los participantes, los cuales consideran el uso de la lengua española como una ayuda esencial en la productividad del aprendizaje del inglés como segunda lengua.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94702</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94702/files/TAZ-TFG-2020-2104.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>A Survey on the Attitudes of Learners and Teachers towards the Use of the L1 in ELT in Spanish Secondary Education.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">A Survey on the Attitudes of Learners and Teachers towards the Use of the L1 in ELT in Spanish Secondary Education.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
