<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Escudero Alías, Maite</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Domínguez Arquillué, Virginia</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This project deals with the evolution of the fairy tale “Rumpelstiltskin” from its first version written by the Grimm Brothers, to two of its feminist rewritings: Emma Donoghue’s “The Tale of the Spinner” (1997) and Naomi Novik’s Spinning Silver (2018). This dissertation is devoted to the exploration of recurrent themes in the three versions under analysis, with a special emphasis on the importance of spinning among women as a subversive act of communication and female bonding, and on the symbolic meaning of number three. In the last section, my work traces the evolution of female bonding, with a special devotion to Novik’s work: from its absence in the original fairy tale, to its presence in Donoghue’s version and its subsequent transformation into betrayal and female rivalry. My analysis finally ends up with an exploration of  female bonding in Novik’s text, which reflects some of the main concerns in current feminism debates on sorority and intersectionality. ________________________________________ Este proyecto estudia la evolución del cuento “Rumpelstiltskin” desde su primera versión escrita por los hermanos Grimm, a dos de sus adaptaciones feministas: “The Tale of the Spinner” (1998) por Emma Donoghue, y Spinning Silver (2018) por Naomi Novik. Este trabajo se dedica a explorar los temas recurrentes en las tres versiones que se analizan: la importancia de hilar entre las mujeres como un acto subversivo de comunicación y afección femenina, así como el simbolismo del número tres. En concreto, este trabajo de fin de grado está dedicado al análisis del vínculo afectivo femenino, con especial atención al trabajo de Novik. Primero, el proyecto cuestiona la ausencia de afección femenina en el cuento original, siguiendo con un análisis de su presencia y consecuente transformación en traición femenina en la versión de Donoghue, para terminar con una exploración del texto de Novik, que se desarrolla en concordancia a los debates feministas actuales acerca de la sororidad y la interseccionalidad.&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85372</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85372/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-2114.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>"Thrice proven, thrice true": Female Bonding and the Feminist Legacy of Rumpelstiltskin's story.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">"Thrice proven, thrice true": Female Bonding and the Feminist Legacy of Rumpelstiltskin's story.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
