<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Murillo Ornat, Silvia</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Gállego Guallar, Cristina</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Abstract: As the English language has increased its use in the last decades (Crystal, 1997), linguists have coined what is nowadays named English as a Lingua Franca (ELF). The present study intends to explore the perceptions that both local and international students have towards the use of a non-native language ‒ English ‒ in a country where English is not the official language ‒ Germany. In order to do so, a questionnaire concerning attitude, (mis)understandings, lexicogrammar aspects, accent, and teaching and learning was released to both groups of students. Overall, results revealed that respondents, despite of the fact that their main aim was to be understood and thus achieve communication in international environments, were in general aware of English grammar rules. The study also suggests that many of the students do not try to follow a native accent but keep their own native one when talking in English.  Resumen:  Debido a que el uso del inglés ha aumentado en las últimas décadas, los lingüistas han acuñado lo que hoy en día se llama inglés como lengua franca (English as a Lingua Franca ‒ ELF). El presente estudio tiene como propósito analizar las percepciones que los estudiantes locales e internacionales tienen hacia el uso de una lengua extranjera ‒ inglés ‒ en un país donde el inglés no es el idioma oficial ‒ Alemania. Con este objetivo, se envió un cuestionario a ambos grupos de estudiantes sobre actitud, (mal)entendidos, aspectos del léxico y la gramática, acento y enseñanza y aprendizaje del idioma. Los resultados de este estudio demuestran que los encuestados, a pesar de que tenían como principal objetivo el ser entendidos y así lograr comunicarse en ambientes internacionales sin necesidad de imitar un acento nativo, eran conscientes de las normas de la gramática inglesa.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75235</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75235/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-1362_ANE.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75235/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-1362.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>The Use of English as a Lingua Franca by University Students in Germany</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The Use of English as a Lingua Franca by University Students in Germany</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
