<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Álvaro</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>del Río Álvaro, Constanza</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Arévalo Viñas, Sara</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Prior to his late fictional works, which Robert Louis Stevenson wrote during his stay in the Pacific, he had not been considered a politically committed writer, nor he had seemed to show interest in colonial practices and the colonial enterprise. It has been argued that it was his stay in the Pacific that affected the course of his fiction, as he started to deal with these themes in an explicit way, as well as to show an anti-imperialist tendency. In these late works, Stevenson aimed to portray the effects of the colonizer’s presence in the Pacific, as well as the relationships between the colonizers and the Islanders. The novel that will be the focus of this dissertation, Kidnapped (1883), was published about a decade before his late works and is set in Scotland. Even though Scotland was not a colony of the British Empire, the relationship between English, Lowlander, and Highlander subjects after the Jacobite rising of 1745 shares some elements with that between the colonizers and colonized peoples in non-European colonies. Through the analysis of narration and the themes of cultural imperialism and masculinity in the novel, it will be argued that Stevenson had already dealt with the theme of colonialism in this novel, as well as shown an anti-imperialist tendency. As a result, it will be claimed that this novel could be said to set a precedent for his late works. Moreover, it will be argued that this novel has a postcolonial nature since Stevenson does not only exert a critique on colonialism but also gives voice to the colonized, which are not relegated to a secondary plane and are active participants in the novel.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/76398</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/76398/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-4329.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Identidad Poscolonial en Kidnapped, de Robert Louis Stevenson.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Postcolonial Identity in Kidnapped, by Robert Louis Stevenson.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
