<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Collado Rodríguez, Francisco</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>García Ayesa, Marcos Javier</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>English: The fantasy genre frequently uses the model of the Hero’s Journey described in Joseph Campbell’s The Hero with a Thousand Faces (1949). The protagonist of these stories must embark on a dangerous journey accompanied by his/her mentor figure, face numerous trials, defeat evil and restore the peace of the world. Some novels, however, modify that structure to enhance their narrative techniques and draw for inspiration at the same time. This is the case of Brandon Sanderson’s The Final Empire (2006). This project analyses the use of the Hero’s Journey and the stereotypes studied by Campbell in The Hero with a Thousand Faces in Sanderson’s The Final Empire, shows how those patterns are depicted in the novel and in which way the author tries to detach himself from them. The project studies the four main heroic or potentially heroic figures of the book presented in the narrative (Alendi, Lord Ruler, Kelsier, and Vin), then it compares their development to the stages portrayed in the Monomyth of The Hero with a Thousand Faces and concludes with an analysis of its effects in the narrative of the novel. Español: El género fantástico utiliza con frecuencia el modelo del viaje del héroe descrito por Joseph Campbell en El héroe de las mil caras (1949): el o la protagonista de estas historias debe embarcarse en un peligroso viaje acompañado de una figura mentora, superar numerosas pruebas, enfrentarse al mal y devolver la paz al mundo. Algunos libros, sin embargo, manipulan esta estructura para potenciar su narrativa a la vez que beben de ella como inspiración: es el caso de El imperio final (2006) de Brandon Sanderson. Este trabajo analiza el uso del viaje del héroe y de los estereotipos del libro de Joseph Campbell en El imperio final, estudiando cómo este utiliza dichos patrones y en qué maneras trata el autor de alejarse de ellos. El estudio hace un recorrido por las cuatro figuras heroicas o potencialmente heroicas presentadas en la narrativa (Alendi,Lord Legislador, Kelsier y Vin) y compara sus desarrollos con las etapas presentadas en el monomito de El héroe de las mil caras, concluyendo con un análisis de su efecto en la narrativa de la obra.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75138</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75138/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-2039.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>The Heroes’ Journey: Traces of Campbell’s The Hero with a Thousand Faces (1949) in Brandon Sanderson’s The Final Empire (2006)</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The Heroes’ Journey: Traces of Campbell’s The Hero with a Thousand Faces (1949) in Brandon Sanderson’s The Final Empire (2006)</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
