<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Pascual Oliva, Daniel</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Clavel San Emeterio, Raquel</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The communicative competence has become a priority within English as a Foreign Language (EFL) teaching methodologies, in a way that the learning-teaching process should enable students to communicate their messages effectively in real-context situations, both orally and in written form. There have been several studies that have reported how students’ writing abilities can be improved throughout the application of the principles covered by the writing as a process approach. Therefore, the purpose of this dissertation is to present and analyse a unit plan which is aimed to enhance the writing skills of EFL students and address the gap found in these students in terms of developing successful written texts. This unit plan also seeks to develop students’ communicative competence following the Communicative Language Teaching (CLT) and Task Based Learning (TBL) approaches. After analysing students’ needs, these theories where applied in the implementation of a learning unit plan which leads to the publication of a post in a travel blog. Accordingly, the legal dispositions comprised in the Aragonese Curriculum (Orden ECD/494/2016, de 26 de mayo) are also taken into account. Finally, the unit intends to foster students’ cultural awareness as well as a critical and responsible use of Information and Communication Technologies (ICTs).</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77391</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77391/files/TAZ-TFM-2018-536.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>¡Escribamos sobre mundo!: mejorar la expresión escrita de estudiantes de inglés como lengua extranjera en 1º de bachillerato a través de blogs de viajes</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Let’s write the world!: improving efl students’ writing skills in 1st year of bachillerato through travel blogs</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
