<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Herrando Rodrigo, María Isabel</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Bruna Marzo, Belén</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This paper aims to reflect on the results of the action research which was personally conducted in the English language lessons of a reduced group of the Programa de Diversificación curricular of 4th grade over a three weeks period. The purpose of study was to explore the effects of ICT as a teaching tool in the language classroom. The results are presented in terms of second language acquisition and students‘ motivation. The overall inference of the research is that students have a more positive attitude towards language learning when they are presented with engaging and challenging activities through technological devices that can better meet their generational needs. Nonetheless, results show that students continued with the same language level and skills may eventually were not significantly improved due to the short term nature of study.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/62482</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/62482/files/TAZ-TFM-2017-070.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Apoyo en el aprendizaje de idiomas con nuevas tecnologías: Un estudio basado en la práctica de la enseñanza de idiomas con tecnología integrada</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Assisting language learning with new technologies: A practice-based exploration of technology-integrated language teaching</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
