<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Lacarra Ducay, María Jesús</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Añorbe Mateos, Marta</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Este trabajo es un estudio comparativo de dos motivos presentes en Konjaku Monogatari-shū (Colección de Relatos Ahora Pasados), compilación japonesa de cuentos o setsuwa escrita a finales del siglo XII, y en la tradición hispánica. Debido a la gran cantidad de relatos que conforman la colección, se han seleccionado dos cuentos que inspiraron a Akutagawa Ryūnosuke para su narrativa breve moderna: el cuento 19 del capítulo XXVI (motivo M341, «Death prophesied») y el cuento 14 del capítulo XIX (submotivo V229.2.7, «Flowers grow on graves from the mouths or hearts of holy persons»). En el primer caso, se explorará el origen del motivo de la muerte predestinada como posible sustrato indoeuropeo (origen común) y, en el segundo, se analizará la gran cantidad de coincidencias que nacen de un motivo religioso a pesar de tratarse de culturas separadas con creencias diferentes (tesis poligenética).&lt;br /&gt;Abstract: this essay is a comparative study of two motifs present in the Japanese folktales (setsuwa) collection Konjaku Monogatari-shū (Tales of Times Now Past), written in the late 12th century, and in the Hispanic tradition. Due to the large number of folktales in the collection, we have selected two tales that inspired Akutagawa Ryūnosuke in his short modern narrative: the tale 19 of chapter XXVI (motif M341, «Death prophesied») and the tale 14 of chapter XIX (submotif V229.2.7, «Flowers grow on graves from the mouths or hearts of holy persons»). In the first case, we will explore the origin of the motif as a possible Indo-European substratum (common origin) and, in the second case, we will analyze many coincidences that rise from a religious motif, despite the fact that they are separated cultures with different beliefs (polygenetic thesis). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85210</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Lingüística General e Hispánica</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85210/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-2932.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Filología Hispánica</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Tipos y motivos folclóricos comunes entre cuentos japoneses y españoles: de la Edad Media a nuestros días.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Common Folkloric Types and Motifs between some Japanese and Spanish Folktales: from the Middle Age until Nowadays.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
