<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Plo Alastrué, Ramón</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Castelló Logroño, Marta Salomé</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>ABSTRACT&lt;br /&gt;The topic of this dissertation is euphemism. Starting from a brief description of its main linguistic and semantic features as well as the basic literature on the subject, I then focus on the common techniques used in its translation. To exemplify these techniques, I have chosen the two existing translations into Spanish, one in peninsular Spanish (1995) by Gian Castelli and the other in Mexican Spanish (1995) by Guadalupe Pineda, of the best-seller Politically Correct Bedtime Stories (1994) by James F. Garner, a reinterpretation of traditional fairy tales from a modern perspective.  The particular stories chosen for their comparison are “The Three Codependent Goats Gruff” and “Cinderella” –two narrations where euphemism plays an important role in the exemplification of Politically Correct language which is one of the main features of Garner’s style. &lt;br /&gt;My analysis includes a classification of the function of each euphemistic expression together with its translation into these two versions and an identification of the technique used in each case. Finally, I provide a brief comment on the cultural clues necessary to interpret each euphemism as well as a contrastive evaluation of how faithfully the meaning of the original euphemism has been conveyed in each of the translations. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/88818</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/88818/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-4337.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>The Translation of Euphemism: A Comparative Analysis between the Mexican and Peninsular Spanish Translations of Politically Correct Bedtime Stories (1994) by James F. Garner.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The Translation of Euphemism: A Comparative Analysis between the Mexican and Peninsular Spanish Translations of Politically Correct Bedtime Stories (1994) by James F. Garner.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
