<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Azcona, María del Mar</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Ventura Franco, Itziar</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2020</dc:date>
    <dc:description>“Nosedive” is the first episode in the third season of Black Mirror. The episode premiered on Netflix on October 21st, 2016 and was directed by Joe Wright. In “Nosedive”, Lacie Pond (Bryce Dallas Howard) lives in a world that classifies people depending on their score in an unnamed app. This society is organized on the basis of one’s ratings, that is, the number of stars on somebody’s social interactions. This essay explores the three main characters of the episode “Nosedive” and their relationship with the rating system in order to understand how the socio-economic status of women in a hypermodern society can be affected by their online (non)validation. It starts with a section on Simon Gottschalk’s The Terminal Self, which contextualizes the analysis of the episode. The analysis of the episode classifies the three female characters depending on their rating and their attitude towards it. Since the three main characters are women, the gender implications of characters’ relationship with technology are also brought to light.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94724</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94724/files/TAZ-TFG-2020-1886.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>The Hypermodern Woman: Female Characters and Technology in Black Mirror’s “Nosedive”.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The Hypermodern Woman: Female Characters and Technology in Black Mirror’s “Nosedive”.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
