<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Azcona Montoliú, María del Mar</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Santamaría Ibor, Victoria</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2020</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This essay sets out to explore the limits and contradictions of the existent readings of Jennifer’s Body through its representation of female monstrosity. It starts with a section on the representation of female monsters in both horror and rape-revenge films and, in particular, given the age of the main characters in Jennifer’s Body, of the monstrous teenage girl. The analysis of the film is divided in three parts. The first part looks at the use of irony and self-consciousness in the satanic ritual scene in relation to the film’s portrayal of male violence against women. The second part reads Jennifer’s monstrosity in the light of her neoliberal, individualist and over-sexualised femininity. The last section explores the complex relationship between Jennifer and Needy, which makes both of them monstrous in their own different manners. As will be argued, the film’s specific use of the conventions of the horror genre regarding gender roles is both a feminist denounce of a patriarchal system and a perpetuation of the same clichés the film wants to subvert.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94711</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94711/files/TAZ-TFG-2020-2016.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>“Hell is a Teenage Girl”: Female Monstrosity in Jennifer's Body.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">“Hell is a Teenage Girl”: Female Monstrosity in Jennifer's Body.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
