<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Carlos Orús Sanclemente</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Anyang Kong</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Tourism is vital in the Spanish economy, and the number of outgoing Chinese tourists are continuously increasing every year. However, Spain’s potential as a tourist destination and the number of outgoing Chinese tourist visiting the country does not align. Although more than half of Chinese tourists travel to Europe, they are not particularly interested in the “sol y playa” tourism of Spain. In an effort to understand the discrepancy between the efforts of Spain as a tourist destination and the number of Chinese tourists visiting the country, this study focused on characterizing the the travel behavior of Chinese tourists to Spain and understanding the behavioral motivation that primarily affects Chinese tourists. In this study, a questionnaire survey was designed to investigate the impact of various factors on Chinese tourists’ image perceptions and the main factors that influence the choice of destination namely: push factor (motivations), pull factors (attractions), internal moderators (personal characteristics), and external moderators (media influence). After analyzing the data with SPSS software, the main results are discussed. The project ends with a series of recommendations for both research and management, together with limitations and future research lines.&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86528</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Dirección de Márketing e Investigación de Mercados; Área de Comercialización e Investigación de Mercados</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86528/files/TAZ-TFM-2019-1538.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Dirección y Planificación del Turismo</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Estudio sobre las características de comportamiento de los turistas chinos en España</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Study on Behavioral Characteristics of Chinese Tourists to Spain</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
