<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Gil, Victoria</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Ayete García, Beatriz</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>PBL GAMIFIED: A LUDIC APPROACH FOR THE ENGLISH CLASSROOM IN 4ESO is an approximation to the EFL area in the second cycle of the ESO stage, more specifically as the combination of the PBL approach with gamification elements. The Learning Unit included in the dissertation abide by the educational framework provided by both the Spanish and Aragonese curriculum, as well as the theoretical framework described by the Communicative Language Teaching approach.&lt;br /&gt;The proposal aims at answering the demand for dynamic and cooperative strategies in order to help reduce absenteeism rates and provide learners with tools which can promote the development of the European key competences model, emphasizing the communicative competence and social and civic competence, as well as crosscurricular values. The proposal springs from the field observation carried out during the placement period carried out as part of the master's degree in teacher training for secondary and upper secondary school education, vocational training, and languages, sport and art studies (especialidad: Lengua Extranjera: inglés).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86635</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86635/files/TAZ-TFM-2019-1002.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>ABP gamificado: una aproximación lúdica para la clase de inglés en 4ºESO</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">PBL gamified: a ludic approach for the english classroom in 4ESO</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
