<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Orús Sanclemente, Carlos</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Simonyan Harutyunyan, Davit</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The inclusion of Internet in all society field has supposed great changes in the personal and profesional relationships. In this present Project aims to analyze the impact that social media has on the broadcast of the plastic arts as well as explore the implications these have for the artist as a means of promoting and recognizing. More specifically, through research based cuasiexperimental design and that collects web analitic measurements, about that social media (Facebook or Instagram) has a higher degree of repercusion, as well as determine the type of publications (photo or video, sponsores content, competition) that generate the best result in the broadcasting of art content. Finally pretend to know what are the different sectors of society show interest in artistic creations. This Project has the intention of creat a conceptual basis to help artists who are looking on the Internet and their comunication tools, a way to make themselves known.&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85481</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Dirección de Márketing e Investigación de Mercados; Área de Comercialización e Investigación de Mercados</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85481/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-2113.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Marketing e Investigación de Mercados</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Análisis del impacto de las redes sociales en la difusión de un artista.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Analysis of the impact of social media on the dissemination of an artist.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
