<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Guillén Galve, Ignacio</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>de Benito Bueno, Elena</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The teaching of phonetics is often neglected in TEFL classrooms, especially with adult learners. Among multiple strategies to tackle pronunciation, there are two main approaches: intuitive-imitative and analytic-linguistic. This paper aims to analyze and judge which methodology is more effective to teach adult Spanish learners of English focusing on alveolar fricative sounds. Two groups of learners were asked to complete a pre-test to judge their awareness of the difference between voiced and voiceless alveolar fricative sounds. After receiving intuitive-imitative or analytic-linguistic instruction they had to complete a similar test. Results showed that the intuitive-imitative approach was useful for oral perception exercises whereas the analytic-linguistic one helped students to predict the occurrence of voiceless or voiced alveolar fricatives. Thus, the methodologies used were useful for individual purposes but a combination of them would result in a better understanding and production of intelligible sounds. Therefore, TEFL teachers should not dismiss a conscious approach to phonetics with the aim of improving students’ pronunciation.&lt;br /&gt;A menudo la enseñanza de la fonética del inglés como lengua extranjera es ignorada, especialmente cuando los estudiantes son adultos. Existen múltiples estrategias para enseñar la pronunciación; entre ellas, dos de las más importantes son la intuitiva-imitativa y la analítica-lingüística. Este trabajo pretende analizar y evaluar estas dos metodologías para la enseñanza de la pronunciación de los sonidos fricativos alveolares en lengua inglesa. Dos grupos de estudiantes completaron un pre-test para averiguar sus conocimientos previos sobre los sonidos estudiados. A continuación recibieron formación siguiendo una de las dos metodologías y al finalizar completaron un post-test. Los resultados mostraron que la estrategia intuitiva-imitativa era efectiva para los ejercicios de percepción oral mientras que el enfoque analítico-lingüístico ayudó a los estudiantes a predecir mejor la ocurrencia de los sonidos fricativos alveolares. Por tanto, parece que una combinación de ambos métodos ayudaría al alumnado a comprender y producir sonidos inteligibles. Estos resultados sugieren que se debería tener en cuenta la enseñanza de la fonética del inglés con el objetivo de mejorar la pronunciación de los estudiantes.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85242</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85242/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-2728.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Pronunciation Teaching and Learning of English as a Foreign Language: A Case Study of Two Methods for Learners of English Pronunciation in a Spanish Secondary School.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Pronunciation Teaching and Learning of English as a Foreign Language: A Case Study of Two Methods for Learners of English Pronunciation in a Spanish Secondary School.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
