<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Guillén Galve, Ignacio</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>Mur Dueñas, María Pilar</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Magaña Monterde, Violeta</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This research was created with the aim of shedding some light on the assumption that dealing with phonetic symbols in the English classroom helps learners to improve their pronunciation. Concretely, it explores whether dealing with the phonetic symbols /s/, /z/ and /ʃ/ may help 1st year ESO students to discriminate and produce these phonemes and stablish connections between graphemes and phonemes. Participants were 13 students between 12 and 13 years old who studied 1st year ESO under the British Council Bilingual Programme in a state school in Zaragoza. They were subjected to an initial observation or evaluation (pretest), a training (a fifty-minute lesson that focused on the phonemes /s/, /z/ and /ʃ/) and a final evaluation (posttest). Results showed that dealing with phonetic symbols in the English classroom helped the participants to improve their pronunciation of the targeted phonemes.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77357</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77357/files/TAZ-TFM-2018-841.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>The use of phonetic symbols to improve spanish learners' pronunciation and intelligibility</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">El uso de los śimbolos fonéticos para mejorar la pronunciación y la inteligibilidad de los alumnos españoles</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
