<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Forns Martínez, Carmen</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Fondón Lahuerta, Alma</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2020</dc:date>
    <dc:description>With the intention of analysing in depth storytelling and its use in Primary Education, this project will give reasons for using children’s stories in the English class. After that, affective and cognitive characteristics of children in different stages of Primary Education will be explained and finally, four factors involved in storytelling will be distinguished.  Once objectives and methodology of the project are stablished, it can be found an organised analysis and exploitation of three different stories corresponding to first, second and third cycle. In this section the analysis is centred in certain aspects of the stories and story-based activities will be proposed, following a defined sequence.  After that process, some limitations of the use of storytelling in the English classroom will be exposed and, finally, the main conclusions reached once the research is completed will be drawn by interpreting the differences and similarities of the three stories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/95247</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/95247/files/TAZ-TFG-2020-2637.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Magisterio en Educación Primaria</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Storytelling in the English classroom. Analysis of stories and techniques to achieve oral comprehension</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Storytelling in the English classroom. Analysis of stories and techniques to achieve oral comprehension</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
