<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Collado Rodríguez, Francisco</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>De Arteaga Rosado, Alma</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Abstract&lt;br /&gt;The main objective of this Dissertation is to analyse some of the most relevant topics and the use of narrative style in the novel The Awakening, written by Kate Chopin, as ways to interpret the protagonist’s final decision. Starting from the premise that Edna Pontellier can be understood as a representation of the 19th century New Woman, the sense of alienation, her rejection of motherhood, and her interest in the arts, constitute the main topics analysed in the dissertation. The story centres on her emotional evolution The Awakening are also a reflection of such evolution. At the beginning of the novel, free indirect style and reported speech represent the narrative vehicle to create distance between the narrator and the main protagonist. These two styles help readers, by means of irony and parody, to view from a certain critical distance the environment that surrounds the protagonist and her family situation. Edna’s awakening is marked by a change in the narrator’s attitude, finally close and empathic, and the use of direct style. Thus, these changes in narrative style are crucial for the final understanding of the novel, as they contribute to convey part of a meaning that is beyond words.&lt;br /&gt;Resumen&lt;br /&gt;El objetivo principal de este Trabajo Fin de Grado será analizar los temas más importantes, así como el uso de varios estilos narrativos en la novela El Despertar escrita por Kate Chopin, con el fin último de interpretar el significado del trágico final de la protagonista. Dado que se puede considerar a la principal protagonista, Edna Pontellier, como una simbólica representación de la Nueva Mujer del siglo XIX, el sentimiento de alienación, su rechazo a la maternidad y su interés por las artes constituirán el conjunto de temas objeto del análisis. La novela gira en torno a la evolución emocional de Edna y esta tesis evalúa cómo el uso de diferentes estilos narrativos ayuda a apuntalar tal evolución. Al comienzo de la novela, el estilo indirecto libre y el estilo indirecto representan la vía perfecta para crear una sensación de distancia entre el narrador y la principal protagonista. Estos dos estilos, por medio de la perspectiva crítica que generan gracias al uso de la ironía y la parodia, ayudan al lector a evaluar el entorno y la situación familiar de la protagonista. El despertar de Edna está marcado por el cambio de actitud del narrador, finalmente cercano y empático, y por el uso del estilo directo. En consecuencia, los cambios que se producen en los estilos narrativos son cruciales para la comprensión de la novela ya que contribuyen a transmitir esa parte de su significado que se encuentra más allá de las palabras.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/88845</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/88845/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-4280.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Temas y el uso del estilo narrativo en The Awakening como reflejo de la lucha por la libertad de la protagonista.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Topics and Narrative Styles in The Awakening as reflection of the protagonist's struggle for freedom.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
