<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Fanlo González, María Isabel</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Rubio Cárdenas, Lucrecia Mishell</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The goals of this work are to perform a mineralogical, textural and chemistry characterization of the El Fraile mine (Iberian Range) and to make a comparison between several similar ore deposits. In order to achieve these objectives, different techniques and methodologies (field work, optical microscopy and field emission scanning electron microscopy) have been carried out. The El Fraile mine consists of a mineralization vein-type that fills a trend fault E-W with an approximate length of 150m. It is hosted by Cambric-Ordovician materials. The host rock is a quartzarenite with bioclasts. The mineralogy consist on primary minerals as galena (PbS), bournonite (PbCuSbS3) and minor amounts of sphalerite (ZnS) and plumosite (~Pb2Sb2S5). The gangue minerals are quartz and siderite, along with secondary minerals as anglesite (PbSO4) and covellite (CuS).  From a textural and chemical point of view, two types of galena have been recognized: the earlier (Gn1), with an almost stoichiometric composition and related with bournonite, and the later (Gn2), Sb-rich and formed by replacement of plumosite. Taking into account the mineral assemblage, the form and structure of the deposit, as well as the host rock lithology, a comparison with the classification proposed by Gumiel and Arribas (1987) for the antimony deposits in the Iberian Peninsula has been made. Although there are several significant differences, the Fraile mine could be compared to the association quartz-Pb-Sb-Ag. Furthermore, García et al. (1988) studied two similar deposits close to El Fraile mine, Leonor and Aragón mines, stablishing four depositional stages, with a different mineral assemblage from that studied in this work, which could indicate either a different hydrothermal system or sampling problems.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77501</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Ciencias de la Tierra; Área de Cristalografía y Mineralogía</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77501/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-158.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Geología</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Caracterización mineralógica, textural y química de la mina "El Fraile", Cordillera Ibérica</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Mineralogical, textural and chemical characterization of "El Fraile" mine, Iberian Range</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
