<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Guillén Galve, Ignacio</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Walmsley Ortiz, John</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The present unit plan is based on several UK comedy television shows, and draws inspiration especially from Never Mind the Buzzcocks (BBC). It is aimed mostly at improving the oral production of the students, as this is one of the main issues that students face in the particular group I had to work with during my practice placement.  The five lessons will be structured as part of the same television show, and there will be a score that carries over from each individual lesson. Gamification plays a very important role, since everything in the unit plan (activities, assessment, structure, etc.) is designed to resemble a television game show.  The unit is designed to be both cooperative and competitive. While the plan could also be designed to not include competition, the assigned group is likely to respond very positively to it: they are not competitive about their marks (likely due to a generally low performance) but during the placement period it was observed that whenever they were presented with a challenge they put in more effort. The plan also attempts to develop the student’s creativity through both the subject matter (Music) and the activities themselves, which encourage them to role-play, argue and think differently. Furthermore, contents from the subject of Music are also tackled in this plan, although only to a certain extent so as to not take too much focus away from the main goal of oral and written production.  The main purpose of the present unit plan is to work on oral production skills and their improvement in order to get the students to be equally proficient in all four skills, since the observed group had a deficiency in this area.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77351</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77351/files/TAZ-TFM-2018-879.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>The show must go on: the use of gamification and role-play for improving oral production in an efl classroom</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The show must go on: the use of gamification and role-play for improving oral production in an efl classroom</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
