<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Semsarilar, Mona</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>Mallada Viana, Reyes</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Farooq, Ujala</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Mixed matrix membranes having combined properties of both polymeric and inorganic materials become an integral part in separation technology. Mixed matrix membrane preparation incorporates positively charged inorganic nanoparticles (INPs) with negatively charged polymeric nanoparticles (PNPs) and in the reverse way negatively charged inorganic nanoparticles (INPs) with positively charged polymeric nanoparticles (PNPs) by use of spin coating technique. The PNPs made of poly ((methacrylic acid)-b-(methyl methacrylate)) and poly (2 dimethylaminoethyl methacrylate)-b-(methyl methacrylate)) diblock copolymers were synthesized by use of RAFT dispersion polymerization in ethanol at 70°C. In the same way cationic quaternized poly (2-(dimethylamino) ethyl methacrylate)b- poly (benzyl methacrylate) and anionic poly (potassium 3-sulfopropyl methacrylate)-b- poly (benzyl methacrylate) were synthesizes by use of RAFT emulsion polymerization in water at 70°C. The inorganic counterpart, iron oxide nanoparticles coated with [3-(2Aminoethylamino)propyl] trimethoxysilane (TPED) and Dimercaptosuccinic acid (DMSA) were synthesized and incorporated into the membrane acting as a bridge between the oppositely charged polymeric particles (due to the presence of opposite electrostatic charges). Filtration tests were carried out by using the feed of different pH at various pressures.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/63704</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Ingeniería Química y Tecnologías del Medio Ambiente; Área de Ingeniería Química</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/63704/files/TAZ-TFM-2017-516.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/63704/files/TAZ-TFM-2017-516_ANE.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario Erasmus Mundus en Ingeniería de Membranas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Magneto-Responsive Nano Structured Membranes from Block Copolymer Particle</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Magneto-Responsive Nano Structured Membranes from Block Copolymer Particle</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
