<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Forns Martínez, Carmen</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>de Diego Oliver, Sofía</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The use of audiovisual materials is not widespread in the regular classes of a Spanish school, in fact it is rarely implemented. The traditional books and audiotapes are still the most common method used by teachers. There are a lot of scholars that claim that its use foster the students' skills and increase their motivation. Furthermore, it is important to adapt to the current times, where students belong to the digital generation using these materials on a daily basis. In order to solve this problem, a teaching unit with this kind of aids integrated in its five lessons will be proposed. Thanks to it, students will develop their key competences and improve their SL performance, especially their listening skill. &lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86549</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86549/files/TAZ-TFM-2019-1374.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Materiales audiovisuales en el aula de inglés como lengua extranjera</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Audiovisual Materials in an EFL Class</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
