<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Forns Martínez Carmen</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Joven Lahoz, Raquel</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This project consists on the selection of songs as one of the many resources that can be used in the classroom when it comes to teach a foreign language. However, we are not referring to the kind of songs that are found in the text books, but in real songs, the ones that surround us all the time on the media. In order to know whether this kind of songs are beneficial or not in the classroom we will considerate first of all the opinion that some experts have on the matter. After that we will design a class in which its activities are based on a song and we will obtain our own conclusions. Finally, we will evaluate the results and compare them with the theories previously mentioned. As a result we will have an idea about the positive and negative implications of songs in the classroom that will help us as teachers to improve our intervention on the Educative System.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/14650</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/14650/files/TAZ-TFG-2014-746.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>songs</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>resources</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>classroom</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>foreign language</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>beneficial</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>design</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Maestro Educación Primaria</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>About songs as a resource for education</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
