<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Bohenel, Martin</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>García Hernández, César</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Escudero Pérez, Jesús</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This project is based on the Subject of Smart Design, in the University of Technology, Sydney, Australia. It revolves around the idea of looking for a topic/issue and addressing it with an electronic product. After initial research of general topics, the problem chosen was overpopulation in public spaces, such as restaurants, museums, parks, etc.&lt;br /&gt;This starting point is where the actual research began, choosing the right user,&lt;br /&gt;environment and unveil problems such as data privacy was mainly empirical and&lt;br /&gt;based on real collected data. After having a general idea the ideation started&lt;br /&gt;with possible ways of establishing a product system, that would help to address&lt;br /&gt;the pleading problem. This part was also boosted by the elaboration of a functional&lt;br /&gt;prototype, that gave much more reliable feedback. The final part is where all the&lt;br /&gt;detail were nailed down and where minor flaws were corrected, all the technical&lt;br /&gt;part is defined in this part.&lt;br /&gt;All things considered, this product addressed overpopulation focusing on an&lt;br /&gt;electronic product, there is a lot of room for improvement due to university limitations, but the idea was well accepted amongst the users and the interviewed people. Organizing people through an electronic product is a way of relief not&lt;br /&gt;a solution to overpopulation which is a problem that concerns us all and cannot be&lt;br /&gt;ignored.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/90135</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Ingeniería de Diseño y Fabricación; Área de Expresión Gráfica de la Ingeniería</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/90135/files/TAZ-TFG-2020-017.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Ingeniería en Diseño Industrial y Desarrollo de Producto</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Sobrepoblación, midiendo personas en interiores poblados</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Overpopulation, measuring people in indoor crowded spaces</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
