<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Guillén Galve, Ignacio</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Sancho Sierra, Cristina</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
    <dc:description>El objetivo principal de este trabajo es mostrar cómo las llamadas weak forms en el inglés hablado son frecuentemente mal utilizadas por los hablantes de inglés como lengua extranjera, dando como resultado numerosos malentendidos. La información utilizada para este estudio se obtuvo de artículos escritos por autores especializados en este campo, así como de materiales de enseñanza que actualmente se utilizan en España. Finalmente, se sugiere la posibilidad de mejorar la competencia fonológica de los estudiantes, tanto en producción como en percepción, aplicando nuevos enfoques que pudieran potenciar la enseñanza de las destrezas orales en la lengua inglesa. Abstract The major objective of this essay is to show how weak forms are frequently misused among speakers of English as a foreign language, giving as a result numerous misunderstandings. The data used for this study were obtained from papers written by specialized scholars on this field and also actual teaching materials, which were chosen because they are now used in Spain. It was concluded that learners of English as a foreign language could improve their phonological competence, in both production and perception, if recent approaches were applied to teaching oral skills including phonology.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/31234</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/31234/files/TAZ-TFG-2014-1744.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>weak forms</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>english rhythm</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>accent</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>stress-timed</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Achieving Intelligibility in Spoken English: the Role of Weak Forms</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
