<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Pérez Llantada, Carmen</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Ramón Puertas , Carmen</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The purpose of this study was to investigate the relation between the attitude and the frequency of use of Communicative Strategies in Spanish learners that learn English as a second (foreign) language. The selected population was administered a questionnaire that they had to fill in at the end of an informal language exchange. Also, short interviews were conducted to find out the reasons why they used communicative strategies. In order to compare the students’ attitudes and frequency of use of communicative strategies a statistical analysis was carried out. Overall, results showed, firstly, that students were aware of their use of communicative strategies, in particular, the use of achievement strategies. Secondly, the analysis revealed a relationship between attitudes and strategy use. The study sheds light on some factors that seem to determine their choice of strategies, above all, the learner’s personality and the situational context.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/78509</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/78509/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-159.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Estudio exploratorio sobre el uso de estrategias comunicativas en los estudiantes españoles en encuentros informales de intercambio de idiomas</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">An Exploratory Study of Spanish Learners’ Use of Communicative Strategies in Informal Language Exchange Encounters</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
