<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Echeverría Domingo, Julia</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Saturque Hernanz, Laura</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2020</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This dissertation explores the representation of time and space as related to dreamscapes in Christopher Nolan’s Inception (2010). The film belongs to the genre of puzzle films, a genre characterised by the disruption of traditional storytelling techniques, and it presents a multi-layered narrative intrinsically linked to the concept of the subconscious. The film is contextualized here within the sociocultural context in which this genre has flourished, as well as within Nolan’s filmography. The dissertation pays particular attention to the modularity of Inception’s narrative, as it shapes the complex plot, the psychological depth and the spatio-temporal distortion of its different narrative layers. Moreover, the analysis also focuses on the metafictional allegories and the presence of psychologically traumatised protagonists that permeate Nolan’s works and contribute to Inception’s intricacy.&lt;br /&gt;KEYWORDS: Inception, puzzle films, modularity, Christopher Nolan, subconscious, layers, allegory&lt;br /&gt;Este trabajo explora la representación del espacio y el tiempo en relación a los sueños en Origen (Christopher Nolan, 2010). Esta película pertenece al género de las películas puzle, las cuales se caracterizan por la alteración de técnicas de narración tradicionales, y presenta una narrativa con diversos niveles que van íntimamente ligados al concepto del subconsciente. Es importante tener en cuenta el contexto sociocultural que favoreció el surgimiento de este género y entenderlo asimismo como parte intrínseca de la filmografía de Nolan. El trabajo presta especial atención a la modularidad de Origen, ya que da forma al argumento, la profundidad psicológica y la distorsión espacio-temporal de las distintas capas narrativas. Además, el análisis también se centra en las alegorías metaficcionales y en la presencia de protagonistas psicológicamente traumatizados, que son una constante en las obras de Nolan y que contribuyen a la complejidad de Origen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94739</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94739/files/TAZ-TFG-2020-1774.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>“Downwards is the Only Way Forwards”: Layered Dreamscapes and Metafictional Allegories in Christopher Nolan’s Inception.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">“Downwards is the Only Way Forwards”: Layered Dreamscapes and Metafictional Allegories in Christopher Nolan’s Inception.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
