<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Luzón Marco, María José</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Blasco Rincón, Carolina</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Information and Communication Technologies (ICTs) are present in every individual's life and have been seen as beneficial tools in education, since they facilitate the learning process. This dissertation aims to present a WebQuest as a tool for helping 1st ESO students of the IES Tiempos Modernos in the acquisition of both language and content input in the Content and Language Integrated Learning (CLIL) classroom. The aforementioned WebQuest has been designed for a Biology and Geology course following the principles of effective learning and the premises of CLIL. The topic chosen is vertebrate animals, what corresponds to unit 6 of the textbook in use. The contents were analysed and a creative and engaging activity was created: students had to design a Zoo of the Rarity to attract tourists to Saragossa in groups. Consequently, this proposal is also based on the guidelines of cooperative learning.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77394</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77394/files/TAZ-TFM-2018-531.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>The webquest as a learning tool in the clil classroom: a proposal for a biology and geology course</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The webquest as a learning tool in the clil classroom: a proposal for a biology and geology course</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
