<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Gómez Marquínez, Alejandra</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Brown Tirapu, Henry</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Abstract&lt;br /&gt;During my placement period in La Anunciata, a private with a state funding school in Zaragoza, I attended several ESO lesson from different years. Here, I observed that there was little interaction between students during class activities. Therefore, the main aim of this Dissertation is to design a learning unit that focused on a PBLL in which the activities designed around student interaction are essential in order to advance in the project. This lesson plan is based on several communicative language teaching and cooperative principles. These principles will also be essential for the development of communicative competences. Furthermore, the guidelines provided by the LOMCE Aragonese Curriculum for ESO have been taken into account for the development of this unit.&lt;br /&gt;Resumen&lt;br /&gt;Durante mi periodo de practicas en el Colegio La Anunciata, un colegio concertado de Zaragoza, asistí a varias clases de diferentes años de la ESO. Durante este periodo, pude observar que la interacción entre alumnos durante las actividades realizadas en clase era escasa. Por tanto, el objetivo de mi trabajo es diseñar una unidad didáctica basada en el método PBLL en el que las actividades estén orientadas a la interacción entre estudiantes y que éstas sean esenciales para el progreso del proyecto. La fundamentación teórica de esta unidad se basa en el Método Comunicativo y en el trabajo cooperativo. Además, se ha llevado a la práctica las recomendaciones propuestas en el Currículo Aragonés de la ESO.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86760</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86760/files/TAZ-TFM-2019-520.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Student interaction through a PBLL approach: An attempt to place peer interaction at the core of the Teaching/Learning process. “Social Media: Utopia and Dystopia through BlackMirror”</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Student interaction through a PBLL approach: An attempt to place peer interaction at the core of the Teaching/Learning process. “Social Media: Utopia and Dystopia through BlackMirror”</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
