<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Teresa Nogueras, José María de</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>Ibarra García, Manuel Ricardo</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Fernández-Pacheco Chicón, Amalio</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This thesis is devoted  to the creation and study of micro and nanostructures using top-down methods, for possible applications in nanoelectronics and information storage, with special emphasis on magnetic nanostructures for applications in spintronics. We have studied (half-metal) epitaxial Fe3O4 thin films, we have developed a new method using a focused-ion-beam to fabricate atomic-sized nanoconstrictions, and we have studied Pt, W and Co- based nanowires created by focused-electron/ion beam-induced-deposition.  Esta tesis está dedicada a el estudio de micro y nanoestructuras, fabricadas mediante técnicas &amp;quot;top-down&amp;quot;, con posibles aplicaciones en nanoelectrónica y almacenamiento de información, con especial atención en estructuras magnéticas para su aplicación en espintrónica. Hemos estudiado láminas delgadas epitaxiales del material medio-metálico Fe3O4, hemos desarrollado un nuevo método para la fabricación de nanoconstricciones de tamaño atómico, y hemos estudiado nanohilos de Pt, W y Co depositados mediante haces  focalizados de electrones e iones.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/3871</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Física de la Materia Condensada</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/3871/files/TESIS-2009-077.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Nanotechnolgy</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>nanolithography</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>spintronics</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>nanomagnetism</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>information technology</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>nanoelectronics/nanotecnología</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>nanolitografía</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>espintrónica</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>nanomagnetismo</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>tecnología de la información</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>nanoelectrónica</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Electrical conduction and magnetic properties of nanoconstrictions and nanowires created by focused electron/ion beam and of Fe3O4 thin films</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TESIS</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
