<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Forns Martinez, Carmen</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Ibáñez López-Quintana, Lidia</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>When Estonia regained its independence from the Soviet regime, and as a consequence of the reform of its educational system, taking as a reference what they did in their neighbouring country Finland. Some analysts have defined it as the educational miracle in Estonia, being ratified for the results achieved in the PISA reports. The factors that have been identified as successful in the Estonian Educational System are equal opportunities for all of their young people, the great concern in families for students to have quality training, access to technology from a very early age at schools. Besides, the stability of the education legislation have achieved PISA results, where students stand out for not having low grades, rather than for having some students with very high grades, that is, there is little dispersion. On the other hand, it is interesting to know which innovations are being used by some schools in Estonia, focusing on those that are being incorporated into the Peetri Lasteaed Pohikool School in Tallinn.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75169</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75169/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-1652.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Magisterio en Educación Primaria</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Estonian education system vs Spanish education system</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Estonian education system vs Spanish education system</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
