<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Pellicer Ortín, Silvia</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Cantera Martínez, Elena</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2017</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Gender stereotypes are social constructs according to which different roles, traits or preferences are expected from females and males. These stereotypes reflect gender discrimination, which still remains in the society and thus, in our schools. This dissertation is intended to analyse to which extent the context of English as a Foreign Language may be an agent of change while facing gender stereotypes and developing students' gender awareness. A case study has been carried out by analysing the students and the teachers' perspectives and the materials used in a particular literacy class. In addition, three lesson plans were elaborated, following key principles from the communicative language teaching and task based approach, and the results were examined to identify possible changes in the students‟ gender bias.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/69556</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/69556/files/TAZ-TFG-2017-5001.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Magisterio en Educación Primaria</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>English as a foreign language context: an agent of change to counteract gender-based stereotypes in the primary classroom</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">English as a foreign language context: an agent of change to counteract gender-based stereotypes in the primary classroom</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
