<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Luzón Aguado, Virginia</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Sánchez Orduna,  Alba</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>ABSTRACT: This dissertation is an innovative educational proposal designed to solve a specific weakness detected during my experience in the Practicum period of the Master’s course in the charter school Escuelas Pías Pompiliano, located in Zaragoza. After examining the coursebook used in the classroom, I could observe that there was a dominant presence of the United Kingdom and the United States of America in the activities it proposed, which concluded in the lack of representation of other English-speaking communities. Thus, territories belonging to the “Inner Circle” of English like Canada, Australia, New Zealand, South Africa and the Republic of Ireland were given a limited or inexistent representation in the EFL classroom, which didn’t provide a complete consciousness and understanding of the wide diversity of English-speaking communities. The Unit Plan will therefore propose a solution to this detected gap, incorporating cultural, historical and geographical aspects from those countries throughout the activities of the lessons in order to normalise their presence in the EFL classroom. This dissertation will consider academic works and studies regarding the importance of providing cultural diversity in the EFL classroom, as well as the legal provisions specified in the LOMCE and the Aragonese Curriculum, following their indications regarding the importance for students to value their own and others’ culture and history, as well as the necessity to educate them in terms of diversity and respect to other languages and cultures.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77315</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77315/files/TAZ-TFM-2018-1159.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Raising awareness about the diversity of anglophone territories and cultures in the efl classroom</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Raising awareness about the diversity of anglophone territories and cultures in the efl classroom</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
