<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Martínez Falquina, Silvia</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Alonso Castro, Laura María</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This dissertation will explore the relationship between slam poetry and activism. Its purpose is to prove that slam poetry can be used as an activist weapon against oppression to raise awareness about racism and colonisation, and to awaken social change. The focus in the context of slam poetry will be on the poet Mwende “FreeQuency” Katwiwa, winner of the 2018 Women of the World Poetry Slam, and on FreeQuency’s poems “Dear White People” and “The Gospel of Colonization.” This dissertation will tackle this author’s poetical activity and how the political is already weaved in FreeQuency’s writings. Then, it will tackle how the origin, context and characteristics of slam poetry and the poetry slam favour political topics, and how the interaction between poets and audiences in competitions and through the internet is democratic and used for activist purposes. In the second part of this dissertation, I will analyse how FreeQuency denounces racism in the U.S. and the colonisation of Africa in the poems “Dear White People” and “The Gospel of Colonization,” using slam poetry to raise awareness and promote social change. I will be using the works of Fanon, Du Bois and Frances M. Beal among others to support the analysis. The role that personal experiences play in these poems and the direct style in addressing the audience typical of slam poetry are essential for striking the social consciousness of the public worldwide. Through FreeQuency’s poems and the injustices that they expose, the veil covering the awareness of the audience will be removed, inspiring social change.&lt;br /&gt;RESUMEN: En este Trabajo Fin de Grado exploraré la relación entre la poesía slam y el activismo. El propósito de este ensayo es demostrar que la poesía slam se puede usar como herramienta activista contra la opresión, para concienciar sobre el racismo y la colonización, y para conseguir un cambio social. Dentro del contexto del slam, me centraré en Mwende “FreeQuency” Katwiwa, y en sus poemas “Dear White People” y “The Gospel of Colonization.” Analizaré la actividad poética de FreeQuency y cómo lo político está muy presente en sus poemas. A continuación analizaré el origen, contexto y características del slam y de su poesía, y cómo todo ello facilita la temática política en la poesía slam. También abordaré la interacción entre poetas y público, tanto en las competiciones como en internet, que responde a objetivos activistas y democráticos. En la segunda parte, analizaré cómo FreeQuency denuncia el racismo en EE.UU. y la colonización de África en los poemas mencionados, usando la poesía slam para concienciar y promover el cambio social. Me apoyaré en las obras de Fanon, Du Bois y Frances M. Beal, entre otros, para realizar dicho análisis. En estos poemas el papel que juegan las experiencias personales y el estilo directo de dirigirse al público típico del slam es esencial para despertar la conciencia social del público global. A través de estos poemas y de las injusticias que desvelan, la venda que cubre la conciencia del público cae dando paso al cambio social.&lt;br /&gt;Palabras clave: poesía slam, FreeQuency, activismo, racismo, colonización.&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85123</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85123/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-3233.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>slam poetry</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>FreeQuency</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>activism</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>racism</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>colonisation</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Slam Poetry vs. Racism: Awakening Awareness and Social Change in FreeQuency’s “Dear White People” and “The Gospel of Colonization”</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Slam Poetry vs. Racism: Awakening Awareness and Social Change in FreeQuency’s “Dear White People” and “The Gospel of Colonization”</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
