<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>García Aznar, José Manuel</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Moreno Arotzena, Oihana</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Cell migration in 3D is a fundamental process in many physiological and pathological phenomena. Indeed, migration through interstitial tissue is a multi-step process that turns out from the cell-ECM interaction.  It is a dynamic and complex mechanism that depends on the physic-chemical balance between the cell and its surrounding. Early stage of deep dermal wound healing process is a relevant migratory example, in which the fibroblast is the epicenter: the recruitment of the fibroblasts -by chemotaxis of PDGF-BB- to the clotted wound occurs. Likewise, this work focuses on studying the major underlying mechanisms of 3D fibroblast migration and the main microenvironmental cues involved within. To do so, we have confined two physiologically relevant hydrogels, made of collagen and fibrin, within microfluidic platforms.  Firstly, an integral comparative study of biophysical and biomechanical properties of both gels is presented. In these results, we have overcome the wide diversity of the existing data and special stress has been done in order to compare the microstructural arrangement, resistance to flow and elasticity. On the other hand, controlled chemical gradients have been generated and characterized within the microfluidic devices. Since biomolecules interact as purely diffusive factors or bound to the matrix proteins, in this work, distribution of PDGF-BB and TGF-ß1 across collagen and fibrin gels has been quantified. Finally, by taking advantage of the biophysico-chemical definition, we have characterized the migratory responses of human fibroblasts within the microsystems in the presence of a chemoattractant (PDGF-BB). Our results demonstrate that the local microarchitecture of the hydrogels determines the migratory properties of human fibroblasts in response to controlled chemotactic and haptotactic gradients, in a myosin II-dependent manner.</dc:description>
    <dc:description>La migración celular en 3D es fundamental en muchos fenómenos fisiológicos y patológicos. La migración, la cual resulta de la interacción célula-matriz, es un mecanismo dinámico y complejo que depende del equilibrio entre la célula y su entorno físico-químico. Concretamente, la etapa temprana del proceso de cicatrización de heridas profundas es un proceso migratorio ejemplar, en el cual el fibroblasto es el epicentro: se produce el reclutamiento de los fibroblastos -por quimiotaxis de PDGF-BB- del tejido circundante al coágulo. Este trabajo se centra en el estudio de los principales mecanismos subyacentes de la migración de fibroblastos en 3D y las principales señales microambientales involucradas en ella. Para ello, se han empleado modelos in vitro haciendo uso de plataformas microfluídicas para confinar dos hidrogeles fisiológicamente relevantes, compuestos por colágeno y fibrina. En primer lugar, se presenta un estudio comparativo integral de las propiedades biofísicas y biomecánicas de los hidrogeles. En estos resultados, se ha hecho especial hincapié en comparar la conformación microestructural, la resistencia al flujo de fluido y la elasticidad. Por otro lado, se han generado y caracterizado gradientes químicos dentro de los dispositivos. Puesto que las biomoléculas interactúan como factores puramente difusivos o adheridos a las proteínas de la matriz, en este trabajo se ha cuantificado la distribución de PDGF-BB y TGF-β1, en colágeno y fibrina. Finalmente, mediante esta definición físico-química, se ha caracterizado la respuesta migratoria de fibroblastos humanos dentro de los microdispositivos en presencia de un factor químico (PDGF-BB). Los resultados aquí mostrados demuestran que la microarquitectura local de los hidrogeles determina las propiedades migratorias de fibroblastos humanos en respuesta a gradientes quimiotácticos y haptotácticos, de manera dependiente de la miosina II.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/30660</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Instituto de Investigación en Ingeniería de Aragón (I3A)</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/30660/files/TESIS-2015-021%20.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>ingeniería y tecnología mecánicas</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>ingeniería sanitaria</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>biología celular</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Microfluidic-based 3d fibroblast migration studies in biomimetic microenvironments</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TESIS</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
