<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Mathieu, Chantal</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>Gysemans, Conny</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Espiau Romera, Pilar</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Today, autoimmune diseases are a serious problem for humanity and constitute severe, sometimes debilitating health complications. Approximately 6% of the population has an autoimmune disease and the incidence is increasing worldwide. One of the reasons for their development is the improper regulation of the immune system, in which regulatory T cells (Tregs) play an important role. Genetic and environment factors have a major impact on the initiation and progression of these diseases. Developed countries create a milieu in which cardiovascular, metabolic, and autoimmune diseases flourish. In particular, Western diet, including high-fat, high-sugar, high-protein, and high-salt consumption, along with regular consumption of processed and ‘fast foods’, encourages the development of obesity, metabolic syndrome, and cardiovascular morbidity and mortality. In some recent studies, high-salt diet has also been reported to influence the symptoms of autoimmune diseases and decrease Treg functionality. Therefore, the aim of the current project was to study whether a high-salt diet could trigger the development of autoimmune diseases in the non-obese diabetic (NOD) mouse model, focusing in this dissertation on the development of type 1 diabetes.&lt;br /&gt;Here, we found that a high-salt diet did not elicit type 1 diabetes development in 16-week-old NOD mice with ongoing islet inflammation. These results were unexpected as mice fed with a similar high-salt regimen developed a more severe type of experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis, an animal model for multiple sclerosis. Moreover, high-salt intake aggravated the symptoms of systemic lupus erythematosus, collagen-induced arthritis and experimental colitis. We assume however that the composition of the HSD and especially the origin of its proteins being 24% casein might have impeded the observations. When maintained on a standard chow, which normally contains natural non-purified ingredients, like wheat middlings, wheat germ, and soybeans, NOD mice have the greatest diabetes incidence. In contrast, the introduction of semi-purified casein- or hydrolyzed casein-based diets are the least diabetogenic when mice are maintained on these diets from a very young age. Although our mice were kept until 16 week of age on a natural ingredient diet, the switch to a diet with casein as the major protein source might have prevented the further development of type 1 diabetes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/88037</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/88037/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-2846.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Biotecnología</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>The impact of high-salt diet on Type I Diabetes</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The impact of high-salt diet on Type I Diabetes</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
