<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Oria Gómez, Beatriz</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>García Blasco, Alberto</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Abstract: Romantic comedy is considered a genre whose audience is mostly feminine. However in a genre so easily overlooked by male audiences we can find interesting portrayals of masculinity that are worthy objects of study. This essay examines the portrayal of masculinity in one iconic contemporary romantic comedy: Marc Webb’s 2009 film (500) Days of Summer. Firstly explaining how masculinity is portrayed in contemporary culture and romantic comedy. Secondly analysing Tom’s character in the film context, relating his masculinity to the ideal of masculinity constructed by popular culture influence, the so called “blueprint of masculinity” and Tom’s relation to it. This film is self-conscious about both the conventions of romantic comedy and modern representations of masculinity and delivers a more honest portrayal of masculinity by the end of the film. Keywords: Romantic comedy, masculinity, sexuality, gender, (500) Days of Summer. Resumen: La comedia romántica es un género que tiene una audiencia mayormente femenina. Sin embargo en un género el cual las audiencias masculinas pasan por alto con facilidad, se pueden encontrar interesantes representaciones de la masculinidad las cuales son un buen objeto de estudio. Este ensayo examina la representación de la masculinidad en una comedia romántica contemporánea icónica, a través del análisis del protagonista masculino de (500) Days of Summer, dirigida por Marc Webb en 2009. En primer lugar explicando cómo se representa la masculinidad en la cultura y en la comedia romántica y en segundo lugar analizando el personaje de Tom en el contexto de la película, relacionando su masculinidad con el ideal de masculinidad construido por la influencia de la cultura popular y cómo el personaje de Tom se relaciona con dicha construcción. Ésta es una película que es consciente de tanto las convenciones de la comedia romántica como de las representaciones modernas de la masculinidad, la cual nos proporciona una representación más realista de la masculinidad al final de la película. Palabras clave: Comedia romántica, masculinidad, sexualidad, género, (500) Days of Summer.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75095</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/75095/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-2349.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Manning Up: The representation of masculinity in (500) Days of Summer</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Manning Up: The representation of masculinity in (500) Days of Summer</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
