<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Bueno Lozano, Gloria</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>Moreno Aznar, Luis Alberto</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>Jimenez Pavón, David</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Miguel Berges, Maria Luisa</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The present review sought to examine the recent evidence on associations between objectively physical activity determined by pedometer and adiposity. A search for observational studies was carried out using database Pubmed in May 2013. Of 278 potentially eligible papers, 34 papers were included. Most studies (28/34; 82%) were crosssectional and all used proxies for adiposity, such as body mass index (BMI) or BMI z-score as the outcome measure. Few studies (9%; 3/34) focused on pre-school children. There was consistent evidence of negative associations between pedometer-determined physical activity and adiposity: significant negative associations were observed in 24/34 (71%) of studies overall. The present review supports the hypothesis that higher levels of habitual physical activity are protective against child and adolescent obesity. However, prospective longitudinal studies are warranted; there is a need for more research on younger children, and for more ‘dose-response’ evidence.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/12232</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Pediatría, Radiología y Medicina Física; Área de Pediatría</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/12232/files/TAZ-TFM-2013-757.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Condicionantes Genéticos, Nutricionales y Ambientales del Crecimiento y Desarrollo</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Associations between pedometer-determined physical activity and adiposity in children and adolescents: Systematic review</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
