<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Arizti Martín, Bárbara</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Del Río Juango, Clara</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Abstract Migration has always been intrinsic to humankind. However, nowadays, these movements of people have increased due to globalisation, which has brought about an unprecedented interaction among different cultures, therefore giving place to transculturality. The short story “Full Face”, by Roanna Gonsalves, narrates the struggles of Indian immigrants when moving to another country, mainly focusing on working women and more especially, on the protagonist, who is also the narrator and focaliser. In this essay I am going to analyse the development of events in the story from a transcultural perspective, mainly focusing on the protagonist’s journey and her evolution throughout the story, exploring similarities and differences with the other characters. In order to do this, I have divided my analysis into three different sections: “From Bombay to Dubai: Goan Catholics on the Move”, “Australia as the Promised Land” and “Assimilation vs. Segregation”. In the first section I explain the historical background of the characters as Goan Catholics and the personal experience of the protagonist in an officially Muslim country, showing the clashes between the different religions and her feeling of being an outsider. In the second section I explore the idea of Australia as a paradise for the characters as a western and primarily Christian country. However, the protagonist’s evolution makes her realise it is just like any other country with its social and political struggles. Notwithstanding this, it also gives her the opportunity to escape from traditional Indian social impositions and empower herself, but without completely rejecting her Indian roots. In the last section I cover the characters’ interaction with the host country and how their own decisions and experiences makes them assimilate or be segregated. My analysis makes it evident that sharing the same historical and religious background and being exposed to other cultures does not lead towards a homogenised universal culture, but rather towards new fluid ones which share common elements, showing, therefore, the centrality of transculturality in our current world. Resumen La migración siempre ha formado parte de las vidas de los seres humanos en todo el mundo. Sin embargo hoy en día estos movimientos de gente han aumentado debido a la globalización, que también comprende la interacción continua entre diferentes culturas, dando lugar a la transculturalidad. El relato “Full Face”, de Roanna Gonsalves, narra las dificultades de un grupo de personajes indios cuando emigran a otro país, enfocándose principalmente en mujeres trabajadoras y más específicamente en la protagonista, quien es también la narradora y focalizadora de la historia. En este trabajo analizo el desarrollo de la historia desde una perspectiva transcultural, centrándome principalmente en la evolución de la protagonista, explorando similitudes y diferencias con el resto de los personajes. Para ello he dividido mi análisis  en tres secciones diferentes: “De Bombay a Dubai: Católicos de Goa en Movimiento”, “Australia como Tierra Prometida” y “Asimilación vs. Segregación”. En la primera sección me centro en el contexto histórico de los personajes como Católicos de Goa y en la experiencia personal de la protagonista en un país oficialmente musulmán, mostrando los choques entre las diferentes religiones y su sensación de sentirse como una forastera. En la segunda sección exploro la idea de Australia como paraíso para los personajes, ya que es un país occidental y principalmente cristiano. Sin embargo, la evolución de la protagonista le hace darse cuenta de que es como cualquier otro país, con sus conflictos sociales y políticos. Por otro lado, también le brinda la oportunidad de escapar de las imposiciones sociales de la India tradicional y empoderarse, aunque sin renunciar completamente a sus raíces indias. En la última sección hablo de la interacción de los personajes con el país de acogida y como sus propias decisiones y experiencias les hacen asimilarse o ser segregados. Mi análisis revela que compartir el mismo contexto religioso e histórico y ser expuesto a otras culturas no conduce a una cultura universal homogeneizada, sino a culturas nuevas y cambiantes con elementos comunes, mostrando, por tanto, la centralidad de la transculturalidad en el mundo de hoy en día.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/76422</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/76422/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-4289.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Roanna Gonsalves' "Full Face": A Transcultural Analysis</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Roanna Gonsalves' "Full Face": A Transcultural Analysis</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
