<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Escudero Alías, Maite</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Martínez Moreno, Ignacio</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2020</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The following dissertation aims at shedding some light onto a group of 19th and 20th century poets known as "Uranians" who praised "boy-love" and male aesthetics as sources of inspiration and devotion. The extensiveness of the group makes it difficult to classify them in a precise taxonomy, as different catalogues share a plethora of names and a thorough study on the subject gradually uncovers more unknown members of the group. Most of their inspiration was drawn from the past, as they praised the classical Hellenic lifestyle and aesthetics, for instance, supporting their pupil-tutor dynamics with Plato's Symposium. Interestingly, they are a group who actively displayed homosexuality in their texts in times when it was criminalized. My dissertation proposes a dichotomization of themes in these authors' body of work between homosociality and homoeroticism. More precisely, my theoretical frameworks mainly rely on Eve Kosofsky Sedgwick's theories on homosociality and Edward Prime-Stevenson’s concept of "Hellenic love" as found in a variety of poems which range from formal sonnets, free verse and elegies, just to name a few. Likewise, my work aims at giving them some recognition in the literary sphere as other examples, although problematic, of queer literature, displaying male-to-male relations whilst poetically depicting them with references to Greek culture as well as aesthetically pleasing themes and motifs.&lt;br /&gt;El objetivo del presente trabajo es arrojar luz sobre un grupo de poetas de los siglos XIX y XX denominados “Uranianistas” quienes alababan las estéticas masculinas del “amor por la juventud” como fuentes de inspiración y devoción. La amplitud del grupo hace difícil clasificarlos bajo una taxonomía precisa, puesto que existen diferentes catálogos que muestran una plétora de nombres y un exhaustivo estudio en la materia revela progresivamente más miembros desconocidos del grupo. La ya mencionada inspiración proviene del pasado, ya que alababan el estilo de vida Helénico y su estética, por ejemplo, respaldando sus dinámicas de profesor-alumno usando El Banquete de Platón. Curiosamente, son un grupo que de forma activa demostraban su homosexualidad por medio de sus textos en tiempos en los que esta era ilegal. Mi trabajo propone una dicotomía de sus temas entre la homosocialidad y el homoerotismo. Para ello mis argumentos teóricos se basan principalmente en las teorías de Eve Kosofsky Sedgwick sobre la homosocialidad y el concepto de “Amor Helénico” de Edward Prime-Stevenson en un número de poemas que varían entre sonetos formales, verso libre y elegías. Asimismo, mi trabajo busca darles un reconocimiento en la esfera literaria siendo otros ejemplos, aunque problemáticos, de literatura queer, describiendo relaciones entre hombres a la vez que usan un lenguaje poético con referencias tanto a la cultura griega como temas atractivos estéticamente. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94768</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94768/files/TAZ-TFG-2020-1400.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Uranian Poetry: the Homosocial and Homoerotic Paradox.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Uranian Poetry: the Homosocial and Homoerotic Paradox.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
