<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Lorés Sanz, Rosa</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Ruiz Solanas, Andrea</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2020</dc:date>
    <dc:description>ABSTRACT&lt;br /&gt;The aim of this final dissertation is to provide a contrastive analysis of two translations into Spanish (one by Ricardo Baeza published in 1927, and the other by Mauro Armiño published in 2008) of Oscar Wilde’s The Importance of Being Earnest (1895).  The focus of the analysis is placed in the use of the strategies of domestication and foreignization first introduced in the field by Lawrence Venuti (1995).  The paper seeks to ascertain the extent to which the role of culture and globalization influences the choice of strategies in translation.  In this way, it intends to determine if there is a tendency for the use of domestication or foreignization and, if that is the case, whether it has been influenced by passing of time. The analysis has been carried out through the comparison of the translation of the first and third acts of the play, focusing mainly on the terms presenting cultural connotations. The findings show that the difference between the disconnection between cultures existing in the 1920s in contrast with their proximity nowadays, has a repercussion on the way culture is viewed and treated in translation. As a result, there is a change from the tendency to use domestication in the target text published in 1927 to the preference for foreignization shown in that of 2008. &lt;br /&gt;RESUMEN&lt;br /&gt;Este Trabajo de Fin de Grado consiste en el análisis contrastivo de dos traducciones al español (la de Ricardo Baeza publicada en 1927 y la de Mauro Armiño publicada en 2008) de la obra The Importance of Being Earnest de Oscar Wilde (1895). El análisis se centra en el uso de las estrategias de domesticación y extranjerización que fueron introducidas por primera vez al campo de la traducción por Lawrence Venuti (1995). El objetivo del trabajo es determinar la influencia que la cultura y la globalización tienen sobre la elección de las estrategias de traducción, es decir, comprobar si hay una clara tendencia en el uso de la domesticación o la extranjerización, y en caso de haberlo, si esta cambia con el paso del tiempo. El método utilizado ha sido la comparación de las traducciones de los actos uno y tres ofrecidas por cada texto meta, con especial hincapié en los términos que presentan connotaciones culturales. Los resultados revelan que la diferencia entre el desconocimiento de otras culturas propio de la primera mitad del siglo XX y la proximidad que ahora hay entre ellas se refleja en la manera de traducir estos términos. Por consiguiente, se puede apreciar una tendencia hacia el uso de la estrategia de domesticación en el texto meta de 1927 que contrasta  con una inclinación por la aplicación de la extranjerización en el de 2008.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94761</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94761/files/TAZ-TFG-2020-1485.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>The Use of the Strategies of Domestication and Foreignization in Two Spanish Translations of Oscar Wilde's The Importance of Being Earnest: a Contrastive Analysis.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The Use of the Strategies of Domestication and Foreignization in Two Spanish Translations of Oscar Wilde's The Importance of Being Earnest: a Contrastive Analysis.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
