<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Escudero Alías, Maite</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Pablo Tomás, María José</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Abstract The aim of this dissertation is to analyse how Emily Brontë’s novel, Wuthering Heights (1847), reflects the social and legal changes that affected the condition of children in their process of becoming adults. In a background of an increasing interest in infancy and its mental development, the novel depicts isolated children abandoned by their elders as well as their path from isolation to socialization. For this purpose, this essay is divided into three parts, the first one settles the children in the novel, carrying out an examination of their ages and providing a summary of the main legal aspects that affected them, with a special emphasis on the question of custody. The second part focuses on the environment in which the children grow up, giving prominence to the different types of imprisonment they suffer inside the family and distinguishing between a psychological and a physical one. Finally, the third part analyses the different relationships between the characters, highlighting the absence of maternal figures, and the defective fathers or adults to guide them, to conclude that only through socialization and literacy they are able to achieve a healthier adulthood. Resumen El objetivo de este ensayo es analizar cómo la novela de Emily Brontë, Wuthering Heights (1748), refleja los cambios sociales y legales que afectaron al estado de los niños en su proceso de convertirse en adultos. En un contexto de creciente interés por la infancia y su desarrollo mental, la novela representa a niños aislados y abandonados por sus mayores, así como su camino del aislamiento a la socialización. Para este propósito, este ensayo se divide en tres partes, una primera para establecer las edades de los niños y resumir el panorama legal que les afecta, tratándose especialmente el tema de la custodia. La segunda partes se centra en el entorno de los niños en el seno familiar que los sitúa en un estado de doble encarcelamiento, psicológico y físico. Para terminar, la tercera parte analiza las diferentes relaciones sociales que se crean entre los personajes, haciendo hincapié en la ausencia de una figura materna o de padres capaces para guiarlos, para concluir que solo a través de la socialización y de la alfabetización los niños logarán encontrar el camino hacia una edad adulta saludable.&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85531</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85531/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-1961.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Looking for Heaven: The Abandoned Children of Wuthering Heights in their Path from Isolation to Maturity.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Looking for Heaven: The Abandoned Children of Wuthering Heights in their Path from Isolation to Maturity.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
