<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Orna Montesinos, Concepción</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Ruiz Martínez, Rebeca</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This present paper explores, analyses, proves and tries to provide a solution to the patent need for Intercultural Communicative Competence Development that a group of 56 students of first year of post-compulsory education portray. Thus, trough the convergence of different fields of study ranging from Intercultural Communicative Competence, Communicative Language Teaching and Second Language Acquisition, this document presents a needs analysis and a subsequent pedagogical intervention proposal that aims to erode the existing prejudices in young students today and to promote intercultural interaction by raising their awareness and by providing them with the necessary tools to reflect on themselves and on the others in a more tolerant, thoughtful and communicative way.  The pedagogical intervention proposal has been nominated as “Ten Mini-Pills for Intercultural Communicative Competence Development” in which students are faced with concrete examples of the elements that shape other cultures so as for them to be able to deconstruct their cosmovision and thus integrate the reality of others.  The “Ten Mini-Pills for Intercultural Communicative Competence Development” have been designed in the light of adaptability and easy implementation, so as for them to not only meet the needs of this concrete group of students but of as many as possible.  &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86745</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Filología Inglesa y Alemana; Área de Filología Inglesa</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/86745/files/TAZ-TFM-2019-551.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Máster Universitario en Profesorado de Educación Secundaria Obligatoria, Bachillerato, Formación Profesional y Enseñanza de Idiomas, Artísticas y Deportivas</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>El diseño de materiales para el desarrollo de la Competencia Intercultural Comunicativa en el aula de ILE</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFM</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Designing materials for the development of the Intercultural Communicative Competence in the EFL classroom</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
