<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Simón Gómez, José Luis</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>Luzón Aguado, Aránzazu</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Cases Abadia, Jaime</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This work presents a study about the structure and the relationships between tectonics and sedimentation in the area of Beceite during the Alpine Orogeny. This area is located in the linking zone between the Iberian Chain and the Coastal Catalan Chain. In this geological context, the area is important because it combines the structural style of the Iberian Chain and the structural trend of the Coastal Catalan Chain. This work provides new data that allow improving our knowledge on the evolution of the Alpine Orogeny in the Iberian Plate.  The sedimentology section is focused on the study of different Cenozoic tectono-sedimentary units and, particularly, the sedimentary characteristics of the Peña Galera alluvial fan.   The structural section includes description and analysis of geometry of macrostructures, kinematics and paleostresses. At a macrostructural scale, the study is based on the elaboration and interpretation of the geological map and two geological cross sections, one of them in detail within the area or Peña Galera. At a microstructural scale, kinematical data been obtained for interpreting transport directions of thrusts. The paleostress analysis is based on the orientation of solution lineations in conglomerate pebbles, which were collected in 11 data sites through the Cenozoic series.   During the Alpine Orogeny, three intraplate compressional stress fields were recorded in the Beceite area, with compression directions ENE-OSO, NNE-SSO y NNO-SSE. These compression directions match the main regional stress fields recognized within the Iberian Chain. Finally, it has been possible to propose a structural and sedimentary evolution model during the Alpine Orogeny.</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/76735</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>spa</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Ciencias de la Tierra; Área de Geodinámica Interna</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/76735/files/TAZ-TFG-2018-3239.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Geología</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Estudio estructural y sedimentario de un sector de los Puertos de Beceite (Teruel)</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Structural and Sedimentary study of Puertos de Beceite sector (Teruel)</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
