<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Sebastián Cabeza, Víctor</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>Meireles-Masbernat, Martine</dc:contributor>
    <dc:contributor>Piacentini, Emma</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Albisa Novo, Airama</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2018</dc:date>
    <dc:description>Biodegradable nano/microparticles have extensive value as vehicles for drug delivery and form the basis of several therapies approved by the US Food and Drug Administration. One of the hurdles to overcome in the use of those materials as drug delivery vectors is their availability at industrial scale. Innovation in process technology is required to translate laboratory production into mass production while preserving their desired characteristics. &lt;br /&gt;The transition between proof of concept and application in drug delivery system is not a simple task being the main reason that only a few drug delivery system products arrive to the market. Different challenges need to be overcome to meet the specific requirements of reproducibility, energy consumption, control of toxicity, environmental impact and productivity required for industrial application. Moreover there is a need for methodologies as basis for the scaling up of processes.&lt;br /&gt;The main goal of this work is to develop a methodology for the production of a variety of particles (nano and microparticles). The synthesis mechanisms will be based on emulsification and nanoprecipitation by using two promising production approaches, membrane and millifluidic devices.&lt;br /&gt;The specific goals to achieve are: &lt;br /&gt;- Development of nano and micro emulsification techniques to produce nano/micro particles based on membrane emulsification and millifluidic devices.&lt;br /&gt;- Control and tune the size distribution of particles according to the therapeutic target application (including administration route, biodistribution, target organ).&lt;br /&gt;- Assessment of the proper drug encapsulation/loading to the required sustained release achieve a good control on the rate of drug release as well as on the burst release to improve the sustained drug delivery.&lt;br /&gt;- Study of drug release pharmaco-kinetics in physiological conditions.&lt;br /&gt;- Study the sustainability of the particle production process. &lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:description>&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77118</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Ingeniería Química y Tecnologías del Medio Ambiente</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/77118/files/TESIS-2019-056.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:subject>fenomenos de membrana</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>emulsiones</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>precipitacion</dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>procesos de mezclado</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Advances in particle engineering for pharmaceutical applications</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TESIS</dc:type>
</oai_dc:dc>
