<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Guillén Galve, Ignacio</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Lóciga Latorre, Pablo Miguel</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2020</dc:date>
    <dc:description>The last few years have witnessed the great evolution that the video game industry has achieved. The success of a video game is not only based on the visual and playable aspects, but also in the game localization. The main aim of this paper is the analysis of several examples of dialogue boxes from Final Fantasy VII to identify and discuss the main problems which translators found when translating it. The analysis focuses on the translation of grammatical and lexical errors, and idioms from English into Spanish. The result suggests that localization is a very exhaustive process and that the mistakes seem to be due to a lack of linguistic proficiency and knowledge of the target culture.&lt;br /&gt;En los últimos años, hemos podido observar la gran evolución de la industria del videojuego. El éxito de los videojuegos no se debe solo a los aspectos visuales y jugables, sino también a la localización. El objetivo de este ensayo es analizar varios ejemplos de diálogos de Final Fantasy VII para saber los problemas que los traductores encontraron a la hora de traducirlo. El análisis se ha centrado en la traducción de errores gramaticales, léxicos y expresiones hechas del inglés al castellano. El resultado del análisis deja entrever que la localización es un proceso muy complejo y que los errores encontrados son errores debido a la falta de un nivel adecuado de idioma y de conocimiento de la cultura a la que estaba destinada el videojuego.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94723</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/94723/files/TAZ-TFG-2020-1910.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Failures in video game localization: a comparative analysis of the English-into-Spanish translation of Final Fantasy VII.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Failures in video game localization: a comparative analysis of the English-into-Spanish translation of Final Fantasy VII.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
