<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Oria Gómez, Beatriz</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Auría Laguna, David</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>ABSTRACT This dissertation analyses the representation of queerness in Brokeback Mountain (Ang Lee, 2005). It discusses the term ‘queer’ and frames the movie within the New Queer Cinema movement, discussing how it fits in this category. The analysis explores the issue of repressed homosexuality in the Western genre: taking Red River (Howard Hawks, 1948) as springboard for discussion, this dissertation analyses how Brokeback Mountain represents queerness and the repression of homosexual desire through three main elements: space, silence, and violence. The film opposes inside and outside spaces, bringing the closet to the outside where protagonists are ‘free’ to express their love far from heterosexual rules. The second element, silence, helps them to keep in contact in a hostile environment by means of non-disclosure. When silence threatens to break, this leads to violence, which also results from the merging of both closed and open spaces, thus leadings to a tragic ending for a love story whose representation on the big screen constituted an important step in the normalisation of homosexual relationships in film for a mainstream audience. RESUMEN En este Trabajo de Fin de Grado se analiza la representación de lo queer en Brokeback Mountain (Ang Lee, 2005). En primer lugar, se habla sobre la etimología del término «queer» y se enmarca la película dentro del movimiento del New Queer Cinema, analizando cómo encaja dentro de esta categoría. El análisis explora el tema de la homosexualidad reprimida en el Western. Tomando Río Rojo (Howard Hawks, 1948) como punto de partida, este trabajo analiza cómo Brokeback Mountain representa lo «queer» y la represión del deseo homosexual mediante tres elementos principales: el espacio, el silencio y la violencia. La película opone a los espacios abiertos y cerrados, sacando el armario al exterior, donde los protagonistas son «libres» de expresar su amor lejos de los confines de la heterosexualidad. Además del espacio, el silencio es otro aspecto importante en la película ya que le otorga una confidencialidad que permite a los protagonistas mantener el contacto en un entorno hostil. Cuando el silencio amenaza con romperse, esto conduce a la violencia, que también resulta de la fusión de espacios cerrados y abiertos, lo que lleva a un final trágico para una historia de amor cuya representación en la gran pantalla constituyó un gran paso en la normalización de las relaciones homosexuales en el cine para un público general.&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85298</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/85298/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-2377.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios Ingleses</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Brokeback Mountain: Queering the Western.</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Brokeback Mountain: Queering the Western.</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
