<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/">
    <dc:contributor>Díez Medina, Carmen</dc:contributor>
    <dc:creator>Abad Martínez, Jorge María</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2019</dc:date>
    <dc:description>This bachelor thesis aims to state the processes that led to the establishment of provisional societies or the reasons why there were necessary; to explain the history of those settlements, or the series of events that marked the lives of thousands of people; to tell the stories and vicissitudes of those inhabitants, or how they would not be the same after inhabiting those places. A journey of more than 3 750km through Spain and Sweden, two countries that do not seem to share much background, nor culture, but that, when all is said and done, share much more than they could ever had imagined: from their same pragmatism to their love for the well conducted works.  A shared history revolving around hydropower born in the dawn of the industrial boom that made Europe rise from its ashes. In short, how reservoirs shaped and changed both landscapes and human lives, constituting the perfect paradigm of what can be called a cultural landscape.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</dc:description>
    <dc:identifier>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/84975</dc:identifier>
    <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
    <dc:publisher>Universidad de Zaragoza; Departamento de Unidad Predepartamental de Arquitectura; Área de Composición Arquitectónica</dc:publisher>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/84975/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-3521_ANE.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:relation>http://zaguan.unizar.es/record/84975/files/TAZ-TFG-2019-3521.pdf</dc:relation>
    <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</dc:rights>
    <dc:subject>Graduado en Estudios en Arquitectura</dc:subject>
    <dc:title>Poblaciones temporales: el nomadismo en la Edad Contemporánea</dc:title>
    <dc:type>TAZ-TFG</dc:type>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Temporary Settlements: Nomadism in the Contemporary Age</dc:title>
</oai_dc:dc>
